Got it
知道了
The poor have lost their safety net.
穷人失去了社会保障网。
Well, isn't it just that this next part doesn't let Brother NO name say a few words, right?
嗯，接下来这一部分是不是根本不让无名氏兄弟说几句话呢？
NO name bro is working on this in China, right?
有个不知名的兄弟在中国做这个项目，对吧？
Brother, say a few words.
兄弟，说几句话吧。
Is it today?
是今天吗？
Hey hello hey
嘿，你好，嘿
Hey, uh, can you hear me?
嘿，呃，你能听到我说话吗？
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Hey
嘿
Hello hello uh
你好你好呃
It's like this
就是这样
I'm just here for fun
我只是来玩的
Because my family has been doing this in China for over 30 years
因为我家在中国从事这项工作已经超过 30 年了。
Actually, I was working under a very big boss doing that
事实上，我当时是在一个大老板手下做这件事的。
Anyway, I'm doing this now too.
总之，我现在也在做这件事。
in a sense
从某种意义上说
Because maybe everyone doesn't know about this insurance thing, uh
因为可能并非每个人都了解保险这回事，呃……
Children can inherit their parents' business.
子女可以继承父母的企业。
So in this regard
所以在这方面
It should probably be considered one of the relatively large ones in the country.
它应该算是全国规模相对较大的城市之一。
So I have a bit more experience in this area.
我在这个领域有一些经验。
A couple of days ago I saw the news about ACA's all sorts of crazy price hikes
几天前我看到新闻，说 ACA（平价医疗法案）导致各种疯狂的价格上涨。
it just occurred to me that I should find someone to understand it better
我突然想到，我应该找个人来更好地理解这件事。
Talk about it, talk about it
谈谈它，谈谈它
Well, I think that the vast majority of Chinese people,
嗯，我认为绝大多数中国人，
Including myself
包括我自己
Although I have also studied in the United States
虽然我也曾在美国留学
have also been enrolled in health insurance in the U.S.
他们也已在美国参加了医疗保险。
even got reimbursed
甚至还获得了报销
I always catch colds and run a fever occasionally.
我总是容易感冒，偶尔还会发烧。
However, many people may uh
然而，许多人可能会……
uh, an important issue that many are unaware of
呃，一个很多人都不了解的重要问题。
Because everyone is still young
因为大家都还年轻。
The United States does not have universal healthcare for people before normal retirement.
美国没有为正常退休前的人们提供全民医疗保健。
there is no universal healthcare coverage
目前尚无全民医疗保健覆盖。
There is no safety net for this.
这件事没有任何保障措施。
There has never been so-called non-existent
从来没有所谓的“不存在的”。
It does not have a universal healthcare system either.
它也没有全民医疗保健体系。
What does this mean
这是什么意思？
In China, this is called a primary-level hospital
在中国，这被称为基层医院
secondary hospital
二级医院
People usually go to third-tier hospitals, specifically third-tier grade A hospitals, right?
人们通常会去三级医院，特别是三级甲等医院，对吧？
What is a community hospital?
什么是社区医院？
not even secondary-level hospitals are covered
连二级医院都不在承保范围内。
None of them have been built
它们都还没有建成。
You can understand it as because the hospitals built in China
你可以理解为，因为中国建造的医院……
The land is all provided by the state, right?
土地都是国家提供的，对吧？
Look at those hospitals in the city center being redeveloped
看看市中心那些正在重建的医院吧。
building skyscrapers regardless of floor area ratios
不顾容积率建造摩天大楼
as long as the hospital wants to build it
只要医院愿意建就行
everything has to make way for the hospital
一切都必须为医院让路。
The hospital can just build a new building whenever it wants.
医院可以随时新建大楼。
Natural lighting doesn't matter at all
自然光线完全不重要。
Well, in the evil United States
嗯，在邪恶的美国
You and I might think it can be understood this way
你我或许都认为可以这样理解
Basically, all hospitals nationwide are like Putian-style medical institutions, right?
基本上，全国所有医院都像莆田式的医疗机构，对吧？
just with a longer history
只是历史更长一些而已。
newer Putian-style hospitals
莆田式新医院
Hehe, right?
呵呵，对吧？
If your goal is profit, then openly state that your purpose is profit-seeking.
如果你的目标是盈利，那就公开声明你的目的是追求利润。
I didn't take my medicine today, feeling super cute.
我今天没吃药，感觉自己超级可爱。
Because back then it could have been a church or
因为当时它可能是一座教堂，或者
universities
大学
a very wealthy tycoon
一位非常富有的商业巨头
donate
捐
ah established a university
啊，建立了一所大学
Such schools are average
这类学校的平均水平
But that kind of hospital usually has better business.
但这类医院通常生意更好。
but it was mentioned that
但有人提到……
I previously added those three questions for ALEX
我之前给亚历克斯提了那三个问题。
the first one
第一个
That is to say, his entire medical system is also different.
也就是说，他的整个医疗体系也与以往不同。
Even if he studied at this hospital back then
即使他当时在这家医院学习过
This is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China
这是纳兰哥在中国的医疗报销单。
has its own foundation
有其自身的基础
can be less dependent on this market income
可以减少对市场收入的依赖
Each of his doctors costs hundreds of thousands
他的每个医生都要花费数十万美元。
several hundred thousand
几十万
millions of people trained
数百万人接受过培训
That's not all, not just that
但这还不是全部，不仅仅是这些。
Let me explain
让我解释一下
Let me tell you about the medical training in the United States,
让我来给你介绍一下美国的医学培训情况。
medical student training cycle
医学生培训周期
A person enters university at the age of 18
一个人 18 岁进入大学。
He can become a doctor at around the age of 30.
他大约 30 岁就可以成为一名医生。
12 years
12 年
The average annual cost ranges from approximately $180,000 to $320,000.
平均每年的费用约为 18 万美元至 32 万美元。
that's about 180,000 to 420,000
那大约是 18 万到 42 万。
180,000 to 420,000 US dollars
18 万至 42 万美元
Brothers, the average annual training cost year after year
兄弟们，每年的平均训练费用都在增加。
180,000 to 420,000
18 万至 42 万
Not only is the training system so expensive
培训系统不仅价格昂贵。
It's all about certification and licensing
一切都与认证和执照有关。
you become a doctor
你成为了一名医生
Being a doctor is, in a sense, something that has become rare to see in China.
从某种意义上说，在中国，当医生已经变得越来越少见了。
is a very ancient guild system
这是一个非常古老的行会制度。
I'm just adjusting the beauty filter
我正在调整美颜滤镜
or this person
或者这个人
to maintain the high income of the group already within it
为了维持集团内部已有的高收入
Yes
是的
So there are many doctors in China
所以中国有很多医生。
I know I know many doctors
我知道我认识很多医生
because we have dealings with them
因为我们与他们有业务往来。
Some of them would say they envy the American doctor system
他们中有些人会说，他们羡慕美国的医疗体系。
how much money he can make
他能赚多少钱
I know exactly what to say
我知道该说什么。
Thank goodness it's anonymous now
幸好现在是匿名的了。
No one knows my name
没有人知道我的名字
You're talking bullshit
你在胡说八道。
This this if you were at XiDa
如果你在西大，这就是你
You wouldn't even have a chance to become a doctor
你甚至连成为医生的机会都没有。
Why is it you
为什么是你？
there's no you
没有你
Your family has no money.
你家没钱。
Second, you're not from a medical family
第二，你并非出身于医学世家。
no such connections
没有此类联系
Why on earth should it be your turn to become a doctor
为什么偏偏轮到你当医生了？
Who provides your standardized residency training?
谁提供你们的标准化住院医师培训？
Let me tell you something
让我告诉你一些事
So, let me tell you something
所以，让我告诉你一些事
As for me,
至于我，
I was planning to study 4+4 back then, right?
我当时是打算学习 4+4 的，对吧？
I was planning to do the 4+4 program.
我原本计划参加 4+4 项目。
you know
你知道
That's why I was able to do the 4+4 program.
这就是我能够参加 4+4 项目的原因。
Hey, I have, I have a recommendation letter
嘿，我有，我有一封推荐信。
Hey bros
嘿，兄弟们
You know, I can only get into the program because I have this recommendation letter.
你知道，我能进入这个项目全靠这封推荐信。
You know what
你知道吗
Someone said why am I so low
有人问我为什么我这么低落
Liu Sun'er is lingering here
刘桑儿在这里逗留了一段时间。
Brother, it's hanging right here
兄弟，它就挂在这里。
Yeah, it's just that some of these medical professionals in the country
是的，只是这个国家的一些医疗专业人员……
He wants to learn this
他想学习这个
This has now been essentially eliminated by the 4+4 policy, right?
现在“4+4”政策基本上已经消除了这个问题，对吧？
I'm not sure about the latest situation.
我不确定最新情况如何。
Yeah, it was, then what? It got taken down.
是啊，然后呢？就被撤下来了。
Then what about the second part? Their insurance regulation is also different.
那么第二部分呢？他们的保险监管也不同。
The Chinese insurance regulatory,
中国保险监管机构
Of course, many people have complaints about it
当然，很多人对此都有抱怨。
But generally speaking, they claim to boast
但总的来说，他们声称自己很自豪
It claims to be for the healthcare of the people, right?
它声称是为了人民的医疗保健，对吧？
the common people and insurance companies
普通民众和保险公司
if any of you have actually filed a complaint with the insurance regulatory authority
如果你们当中有人已经向保险监管机构提出过投诉的话
you'll know that in most cases, the insurance regulatory authority sides with the ordinary people
你会知道，在大多数情况下，保险监管机构会站在普通民众一边。
because the two of you can argue, right
因为你们两个可以争论，对吧。
Unless, uh, there's a situation in China
除非，呃，中国那边发生了什么事。
Yes yes yes, it's quite fair on both sides
是的，是的，这对双方都很公平。
what illnesses you had before
你以前得过哪些疾病？
indeed not mentioned
确实没有提及
This is also recorded in the medical history, right?
这一点也记录在病历里，对吧？
This black-and-white written evidence cannot be forged.
这种白纸黑字的书面证据是伪造不了的。
without this thing
如果没有这东西
the vast majority of unclear cases
绝大多数不明案件
Healthcare is all about supporting ordinary people
医疗保健的本质在于支持普通民众。
Because ordinary folks are not medical professionals, right?
因为普通人不是医疗专业人员，对吧？
You come up with so many convoluted clauses
你写出了这么多晦涩难懂的条款。
I don't understand, right?
我不明白，对吧？
Anyway, the money was already paid at that time
总之，当时钱已经付清了。
You can't possibly give me nothing at all, right?
你不可能什么都不给我，对吧？
This is a medical system based on the American and Western model
这是一个基于美国和西方模式的医疗体系
What does it emphasize?
它强调的是什么？
it emphasizes fairness
它强调公平性
so-called fairness
所谓的公平
He is the elephant
他是那头大象
You are an ant
你是一只蚂蚁
We want fairness
我们想要公平。
Everyone, you step on it
大家，都踩上去！
it steps on you
它踩在你身上
Let's try the preview
我们来试试预览功能。
Both parties hire their own lawyers
双方各自聘请律师。
cross-examination, right
交叉询问，右
You want to prove that over 30 years ago
你想证明这一点是在 30 多年前。
that unreported case of pneumonia back then and your current knee
那起未上报的肺炎病例，以及你现在的膝盖问题
Is this so-called meniscus damage related?
这种所谓的半月板损伤与此有关吗？
Let's hear what the insurance company has to say
让我们听听保险公司怎么说。
He believes there is a connection
他认为两者之间存在联系。
provide evidence
提供证据
｛1001｝
his legal team
他的法律团队
his lifelong team said
他毕生的团队说
Please, average citizen A, come here
请普通市民 A 过来一下
Give an example
举例说明
This is just fucking terrifying, okay?
这简直太可怕了，好吗？
Oh because everyone is just like, oh dear
哦，因为每个人都像这样，哦，亲爱的
Because I often encounter this kind of problem
因为我经常遇到这类问题
Someone said, um,
有人说，嗯，
What's the difference between getting insurance in mainland China and abroad?
在中国大陆购买保险和在国外购买保险有什么区别？
Actually, I don't even need to
实际上，我甚至不需要
I said just try applying for insurance yourself and you'll see
我说，你就自己去申请保险试试就知道了。
insuring in China
在中国投保
for example, asking you 33 or 35 questions
例如，问你 33 个或 35 个问题
it's over
结束了
Although each question may appear extremely complex
尽管每个问题看起来都极其复杂。
Once you finish asking, it's over
问完之后，就结束了。
won't ask you another question
不会再问你其他问题了
in some delightful places
在一些令人愉悦的地方
There's always a line underneath that says
下面总会有一行字说：
Is there anything else you think should be mentioned but hasn't been said?
您认为还有什么应该提及但尚未提及的吗？
Well, this thing is legally unobjectionable.
嗯，这件事在法律上没有任何问题。
but hehe
呵呵
This is really going to cause a dispute.
这肯定会引发一场争端。
This is an open-ended contract
这是一份开放式合同。
comrade
同志
And then when the time comes, the banking and insurance regulator says they're here to ensure fairness.
然后，时机成熟时，银行和保险监管机构会说，他们来这里是为了确保公平。
Was there such a clause back then?
当时有这样的条款吗？
Did you answer honestly?
你如实回答了吗？
Did you answer every question that needed to be answered?
你是否回答了所有需要回答的问题？
Oh my god, right
我的天啊，没错
And then, and then, and then, and also, uh,
然后，然后，然后，还有，呃，
Because, precisely because, uh
因为，正是因为，呃
Let's talk about the underlying logic of business.
我们来谈谈商业的根本逻辑。
because domestically, to take a step back,
因为在国内，退一步讲，
there's universal healthcare coverage, right
有全民医保，对吧？
so the so-called uh
所以所谓的呃
Well, let me first make a direct comparison with the US.
好吧，首先让我直接与美国进行比较。
so-called medical insurance
所谓的医疗保险
it primarily serves middle-class and above individuals
它主要服务于中产阶级及以上人群。
Right, right?
对吧？
But generally speaking, there are also those in China that cost a few thousand yuan
但总的来说，在中国也有一些售价几千元人民币的。
the medical insurance that costs tens of thousands a year
每年花费数万美元的医疗保险
That mainly serves the middle class and above
这主要服务于中产阶级及以上人群。
add icing on the cake to build reputation
锦上添花，提升声誉
This circle isn't that big either.
这个圆圈也不算大。
Word spreads fast.
消息传播得很快。
if you don't do it well, right
如果你做得不好，对吧？
Who are you going to sell to next year, right?
你明年打算把产品卖给谁？
So in the lovely United States
所以，在美丽的美国
You have to buy it whether you want to or not
不管你愿不愿意，你都得买。
You either buy it or buy me
你要么买它，要么买我。
And then here comes the uh
然后，呃……
often seen in American TV shows
经常出现在美国电视节目中
everyone will see something like in-network
每个人都会看到类似网络内的内容。
the term in-network out-of-network in China
中国术语中的“院内/院外”
People would ask, is this a secondary hospital or not, right?
人们会问，这是一家二级医院吗？
secondary and above hospitals
二级及以上医院
you are indeed a hospital, right
你们确实是家医院，对吧？
If it's a private hospital, right
如果是私立医院，对吧？
The state also has a dedicated registry for this.
该州还为此设立了专门的登记处。
as long as it can be found in the national registry
只要能在国家登记册中找到就行
that thing of yours can just be called a hospital
你那玩意儿简直就可以叫医院。
The US doesn't have this
美国没有这个
Then who is going to certify that this thing is called a hospital
那么，谁来认证这东西能被称为医院呢？
or what is it called
或者它叫什么来着
Oh, the insurance company, right
哦，是保险公司，对吧？
So the evaluation system ends up being controlled by the insurance companies.
因此，评估体系最终被保险公司所控制。
Just think about the horror in this
想想这有多恐怖
The insurance company pays for it.
保险公司会支付这笔费用。
Ah, this thing in the insurance company
啊，保险公司里的这事儿
he considers it to be something called, uh, good
他认为这是一种叫做……好的东西。
called a proper hospital
被称为正规医院
in the eyes of the insurance company
在保险公司眼中
it is not considered a legitimate hospital
它不被视为正规医院。
This is only the first derivative
这只是导数的一阶导数。
because he has no other choice
因为他别无选择
the state doesn't intervene
国家不进行干预
then the enterprises have to take care of it
那么企业就必须负责处理这件事。
You think it seems reasonable
你觉得这似乎合情合理
What is the second derivative?
二阶导数是什么？
The second derivative is like, oh they need to cooperate with each other.
二阶导数就像是，哦，他们需要互相合作。
I recognize you as a legitimate hospital
我认可贵院是一家正规医院。
I even guide and retain patients
我甚至还能指导和留住病人。
No, I call it customer
不，我称之为客户
patient referral
患者转诊
It's about the patients you get, right?
关键在于你接诊的病人，对吧？
Then you have to give me benefits
那么你就得给我好处。
You've got to give me a discount, right?
你得给我打折，对吧？
What's more, you even have to consult me first about the treatment plan, right?
而且，你甚至还要先跟我商量治疗方案，对吧？
This patient was referred by me
这位病人是我转诊的。
This illness of his, right?
是他的这种病，对吧？
Should it be radiotherapy and chemotherapy or conservative treatment
应该采用放疗联合化疗还是保守治疗？
You ask me first
你先问我
after consulting me
咨询过我之后
You should tell the patient how much is appropriate
你应该告诉患者合适的剂量是多少。
We both reach an agreement
我们双方达成一致
Then you go and tell others
然后你再去告诉其他人。
That is, that is, this is it
也就是说，也就是说，就是这样。
Is this the content from that short video just now?
这是刚才那个短视频的内容吗？
right
正确的
You must start with the cheapest treatment option
你必须从最便宜的治疗方案开始。
If you don't do this
如果你不这样做
I simply won't cover the patient
我绝不会为病人承担费用。
not even aware
甚至都没意识到
Domestic healthcare also has its own issues.
国内医疗保健也存在自身问题。
In the past, everyone in China complained a lot
过去，中国人总是抱怨个不停。
saying 'oh, I'll give you one that insurance covers
他说：“哦，我会给你一个保险涵盖的。”
give you one that medical insurance won't cover
给你一份医疗保险不承保的保单
Hey, you have two options
嘿，你有两个选择
You choose the more expensive option, doctor, sigh
医生，你选择了更贵的方案，唉。
These issues do exist
这些问题确实存在。
Of course, the government has now taken very strong measures to address these issues
当然，政府现在已经采取了非常强有力的措施来解决这些问题。
Right, hmm
对，嗯。
Everyone may have some experience with this
每个人都可能对此有所了解。
You may also know that sometimes it might be overcorrected
您可能也知道，有时可能会矫枉过正。
this this again
这又来了
But in lovely America
但在美丽的美国
This is the norm
这是常态
And then there will be
然后就会有
After the first and second points, we then come to the third point
在第一点和第二点之后，我们接下来讨论第三点。
So why would I come across these real-life cases
那么，我为什么会遇到这些真实案例呢？
Hey everyone, well, for ordinary people, right
大家好，嗯，对于普通人来说，对吧？
The premium you pay is also cheap
你支付的保费也很便宜。
the gemstone you choose is also of poor quality
你选择的宝石质量也很差。
the plan you chose is also poor, right
你选择的方案也很糟糕，对吧？
you you you all these you originally you were excluded
你们，你们，你们所有人，最初都被排除在外了。
Being excluded or whatever, it all comes back to the same source—you understand that, right? The rich, well, it's not for nothing that America is said to be a paradise for the wealthy.
被排斥也好，其他什么也罢，归根结底都是同一个问题——你明白吧？富人嘛，美国被称为富人的天堂并非浪得虚名。
You understand
你明白
those wealthy people, right
那些有钱人，对吧？
Isn't it said that America is a paradise for the rich?
不是有人说美国是富人的天堂吗？
You have money
你有钱
You can find the best doctors
你可以找到最好的医生
you purchase the best
你购买的是最好的
this this this this this this insurance policy right
这份保险单对
You should be fine, right?
你应该没事的，对吧？
there is still a problem
问题依然存在。
Why
为什么
Because when it reaches that stage
因为当它达到那个阶段时
In other words, it comes back to the same point
换句话说，问题又回到了原点。
because there is no universal healthcare safety net
因为没有全民医疗保健安全网。
no one has your back
没人会为你撑腰
There is really no such insurance policy
实际上并不存在这样的保险政策。
they renewed it for you for 30 years
他们为你续签了 30 年。
50 years
50 年
You might already be 70 years old now
你现在可能已经 70 岁了。
However, the past few years have been very good.
然而，过去几年都非常好。
Today, this company is truly shocking.
今天，这家公司真是令人震惊。
He said, 'Ugh, well, I'm not going to cover these things.'
他说：“唉，这些事我就不报道了。”
or if you previously had diabetes
或者如果您之前患有糖尿病
I also give it to you every year
我每年也都会把它送给你。
continue your coverage without excluding diabetes
继续享有您的保险保障，糖尿病保险不予排除。
But starting this year, our company's policy has changed
但从今年开始，我们公司的政策发生了变化。
You really had diabetes before
你以前真的得过糖尿病。
I really can't renew it for you now.
我现在真的无法帮你续费了。
or this condition must be excluded
或者必须排除这种情况。
which medications to exclude for you
哪些药物你应该停用
He can really change it anytime.
他随时都可以改变主意。
Of course, such problems also exist domestically in China
当然，中国国内也存在类似的问题。
is supervised by the CBIRC
受银保监会监管
there's banking and insurance regulation in place
银行业和保险业已有相关监管规定。
Then everyone might notice that there are some things
然后大家可能会注意到有些事情
some products
部分产品
maybe this company and that company have similar names in them
也许这家公司和那家公司名称很相似。
have the same thing
有同样的东西
they are all called so-and-so or such-and-such
它们都叫某某某
these are the ones with the same name
这些是同名的。
These are regulations that only the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission would have at this level.
这些是只有中国银行保险监督管理委员会才会制定的此类规定。
you want to call it this name
你想叫它这个名字
you must
你必须
Actually, this is somewhat similar to ACA
实际上，这与《平价医疗法案》(ACA) 有些类似。
as long as you're called ACA
只要你叫 ACA
You must cover pre-existing conditions
您必须涵盖既有疾病。
You have to admit it, right?
你不得不承认这一点，对吧？
In fact, appropriate regulation is beneficial
事实上，适当的监管是有益的。
It is beneficial for both clients to maintain a balance between the two sides.
保持双方利益平衡对双方客户都有好处。
But anyway in the U.S.
但无论如何，在美国
for this and that
为了这个和那个
including the transgender issues you mentioned about Obama
包括你提到的奥巴马的跨性别问题。
he inserted quite a few personal agendas
他掺杂了不少个人目的。
resulting in that not being the majority
因此，这种情况并非占多数。
To be precise, he takes it as his own
确切地说，他把它当作自己的。
Everyone, think about it, you all, and then brothers
大家，好好想想，还有兄弟们。
Just imagine
试想一下
In regions with half of the U.S. population, totaling 150 million people
在美国人口占一半的地区，总人口达 1.5 亿人
alter all textbooks to promote transgenderism
修改所有教科书以宣扬跨性别主义
All teachers promote gender transition
所有教师都提倡性别转换
from the kindergarten stage
从幼儿园阶段
Alright, let's put these aside for now.
好了，我们先把这些放在一边。
So, let's say if I were really rich, right
假设我真的很有钱，对吧？
I don't even need insurance
我甚至不需要保险。
I can pay everything in cash
我可以用现金支付所有款项。
I have 20 billion, right
我有 200 亿，对吧？
Can't I just pay in cash, right?
我可以直接付现金吗？
There will still be problems
问题依然存在。
What's the issue?
问题是什么？
Sigh, here we go again.
唉，又来了。
The American medical system is plagued by a slew of obstacles
美国医疗体系面临诸多障碍。
including referrals and a bunch of other obstacles
包括转诊和其他一系列障碍
and then
进而
As we all know
我们都知道
American doctors see far fewer patients per year compared to their Chinese counterparts.
与中国同行相比，美国医生每年接诊的病人数量要少得多。
Well, let me, let me, let me give you the numbers.
好，让我，让我，让我把数字告诉你。
On average, an American doctor sees about 30 patients per year.
美国医生平均每年接诊约 30 位病人。
around 50 people
大约 50 人
Is the special department currently performing surgeries or is it just about performing surgeries?
该专科部门目前是否开展手术，还是仅仅负责开展手术？
On average, they see about 4.4 patients per week.
他们平均每周接诊约 4.4 位患者。
That would mean performing about 50 surgeries a year.
这意味着每年要进行大约 50 例手术。
it's about twenty to thirty surgeries a week, which averages to 4.4 per week
每周大约有 20 到 30 台手术，平均每周 4.4 台。
that's seeing fewer than five patients a week
也就是说，每周接诊的患者少于五位。
This then leads to a very critical issue
这就引出了一个非常关键的问题。
Actually, his skill level is
实际上，他的技能水平是
Although he may have the world's most innovative drugs
尽管他可能拥有世界上最具创新性的药物。
Because anyway, the standards for his experiments are lax
总之，他的实验标准很宽松。
But his actual practical skills are poor and not up to par.
但他实际操作技能很差，达不到标准。
Yes, very much so, I just can't say who.
是的，确实如此，但我不能透露是谁。
I have, I have... oh, how should I put it... oh, how should I say this...
我有，我有……哦，我该怎么说呢……哦，我该怎么说呢……
I want to see how to say it, oh, this needs to protect someone's privacy
我想看看该怎么说，哦，这需要保护某人的隐私
It's just a very small matter
这只是件小事。
Let me say it for everyone, old Rockefeller
让我替大家说一句，老洛克菲勒
Young Rockefeller underwent surgery in Beijing
年轻的洛克菲勒在北京接受了手术
This also exists
这也存在。
Then, well, I just wanted to say it's a very minor surgery
然后，嗯，我只想说这只是个小手术。
maybe involving, like,
可能涉及，比如，
for men who are interested in this
对于对此感兴趣的男士来说
a minor surgery involving the urethra
涉及尿道的小手术
performed when the person was in their thirties or forties
手术时该人正值三十多岁或四十多岁。
And then, at the very end during the puncture,
然后，在穿刺的最后阶段，
accidentally punctured one of the urethras
不小心刺破了其中一根尿道
So, as you know, people have two kidneys, right?
如你所知，人有两个肾脏，对吧？
right
正确的
one of them is not working well
其中一个不太好用。
You actually don't know for sure right away, right?
你其实不能马上确定，对吧？
Sigh, and then this Taoist priest stood up, hey
唉，然后这位道士站了起来，嘿。
It's growing
它正在增长
It cannot be cleared
无法清除
one kidney was already rendered useless
其中一个肾脏已经失去功能。
Then you don't discover this problem until you're in your 50s
直到你 50 多岁，才会发现这个问题。
and then you can never replace this gem again
这样一来，你就再也无法取代这颗宝石了。
Because these are all major issues
因为这些都是重大问题。
It's already good enough that they originally renewed your insurance.
他们当初同意续保就已经很好了。
Then in another couple of years when you're in your 60s
然后再过几年，等你六十多岁的时候……
and then they say
然后他们说
it's definitely because you only have one kidney
那肯定是因为你只有一个肾脏。
it's more prone to problems, right?
它更容易出问题，对吧？
such as taking some medications
例如服用某些药物
Previously, this medication was all reimbursable.
以前，这种药物的费用全部可以报销。
Then one day after turning 65, maybe
然后，在 65 岁生日后的某一天，也许
He said, 'Oh, this policy has changed'
他说：“哦，这项政策变了。”
This medication is no longer covered by your insurance.
您的保险已不再涵盖此药物。
Yes, everything is fine when you're young
是的，年轻的时候一切都很好。
as you get older
随着年龄增长
screwed
螺丝
Then this issue is something that even if you have billions
那么，即使你拥有数十亿，这个问题也依然存在。
It's something you can't even save no matter what.
这是无论如何都无法挽救的东西。
It's like, oh my, I don't even know how to put it
真是，哎呀，我都不知道该怎么形容了。
This matter is all real.
这件事都是真的。
I really
我真的
I swear to heaven these things really happened
我向上帝发誓，这些事真的发生过。
So the result is that for Chinese people, it's still manageable in the end
所以结果是，对中国人来说，最终还是可以应对的。
Actually, they're all first-generation Chinese immigrants
实际上，他们都是第一代中国移民。
were all born and raised in China
我们都在中国出生长大。
still know what the situation is like back home, uh
仍然知道家乡的情况，嗯。
I've seen that basically, once they reach a certain age, they all have to come back.
我发现，基本上，一旦他们到了某个年龄，他们都必须回来。
They all have to come back
他们都必须回来
they all have to come back
他们都得回来
He definitely has to come back
他肯定得回来。
If this doesn't come back, you'll lose it, oh dear
如果它找不回来，你就失去它了，哦，亲爱的
I'm here with all this medical English and whatnot
我带着这些医学英语之类的东西来了
I won't say anymore
我不会再说了。
Everyone in China who has ever sought or seen a specialist
在中国，所有曾经寻求或看过专科医生的人
shouldn't instinctively raise an alarm
不应该本能地发出警报
All men are brothers and share the same heart; good things
所有人都是兄弟，心意相通；美好的事物
Good doctors everywhere require the right connections.
优秀的医生都需要良好的人脉关系。
Back in China, you might have managed through scalpers
在中国，你或许可以通过黄牛党买到货。
through insurance companies through
通过保险公司
how can you still manage to find one, right
你怎么还能找到一个呢？对吧？
Such people are somewhat related to you
这些人与你有些关联。
not to mention distant relatives by marriage, just two degrees of separation
更别提远房姻亲了，仅仅两层关系就足以让他们彼此疏远。
Remember who you are, like your sister-in-law's younger sister, right?
记住你是谁，就像你嫂子的妹妹一样，对吧？
This matter can still be said to carry a bit of human compassion.
这件事仍然可以说蕴含着一丝人性的光辉。
this in, in, in the lovely America
这在，在，在美丽的美国
Who are you?
你是谁？
You, who are you? Some distant relative or in-law?
你是谁？远房亲戚还是姻亲？
You are a first-generation immigrant
你是第一代移民。
You're nothing
你什么都不是
Especially since you're still Chinese
尤其因为你还是中国人。
Oh, should I mute myself first?
哦，我应该先把自己静音吗？
Well, just think about it, right?
想想看，对吧？
Just imagine
试想一下
Sometimes the first thing these people do when returning to China is go to the hospital.
有时这些人回到中国后做的第一件事就是去医院。
Yeah
是的
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Sigh, then let's share another case.
唉，那我们再分享另一个案例吧。
You said, then, you kept mentioning this, it just occurred to me
你当时说，你一直提到这件事，我突然想到了。
Uh, uh, uh, as everyone knows, the United States doesn't have universal healthcare.
呃，呃，呃，众所周知，美国没有全民医疗保健。
but Canada does have it
但加拿大确实有。
Right?
正确的？
Canada and the UK have it
加拿大和英国都有它
Then, but actually, their system is quite similar
但实际上，他们的系统非常相似。
it will lead to the situation where the first consultation
这将导致第一次磋商出现这种情况。
You must first consult a family doctor
您必须先咨询家庭医生。
you cannot seek
你不能寻求
the so-called hospitals in China
中国所谓的医院
You can walk in anytime and get treated
您可以随时前来就诊。
It's not like this abroad.
国外的情况并非如此。
The so-called large hospitals abroad
国外的所谓大型医院
is like the headquarters office building of Sinopec
就像中国石化的总部办公大楼一样。
You enter and there's a beautiful receptionist lady
你进去后，会看到一位漂亮的接待员女士。
first ask you
首先问你
Do you have an appointment?
你有预约吗？
Who do you want to see
你想见谁
No, he's not here for our kind of walk-in registration.
不，他不是来参加我们这种无需预约的登记活动的。
He's not here to get a consultation number from us
他来这里不是为了向我们索要咨询电话号码。
This is the headquarters office building of Sinopec, right?
这是中国石化总部办公楼，对吧？
The receptionist asks you
前台接待员问你
very sweetly asks you
非常温柔地问你
Do you have an appointment?
你有预约吗？
Who would you like to see
你想见谁
Then check and verify for you
然后为您核实确认。
If you don't have one, sorry
如果你没有，抱歉。
You won't be able to see
你将无法看到
never see the good
从未看到好处
So first, if there's any issue, please call your family doctor
所以首先，如果有任何问题，请致电您的家庭医生。
However, please be aware that discussing medical conditions over the phone is not allowed.
但是请注意，不允许通过电话讨论医疗状况。
Right
正确的
You must, ah, also pay an additional 50% service fee, ah.
您还必须支付额外的 50% 服务费。
Can you really escape it, huh?
你真的能逃脱吗？
negotiable
可协商
I don't know as much as you do
我懂得不如你多。
And then
进而
Yesterday I said, 'Oh my, I have terrible stomach pain.'
昨天我说：“哎呀，我肚子疼得厉害。”
Can I come next Tuesday?
我下周二可以来吗？
Next Tuesday is not convenient
下周二不方便
How about Thursday morning? Okay, it's scheduled, right?
周四上午怎么样？好的，已经安排好了，对吧？
Oh, you... Attorney Wang
哦，你……王律师
Your problem, oh dear
你的问题，哦，亲爱的。
I don't know what to do either
我也不知道该怎么办。
Alright then, I'll have you go get a few tests done first, okay?
好的，那我先安排你去做几个检查，好吗？
This is still not a hospital, just Lab A and Lab B.
这里还不是医院，只是 A 实验室和 B 实验室。
Then after the tests were done
测试结束后
tests were conducted
进行了测试。
Then, well, you just have to wait
那么，你就只能等了。
The quickest wait is a week
最快等待时间为一周。
Some have to wait as long as three months.
有些人甚至要等上三个月。
Someone said, let me tell you, in our lab...
有人说，让我告诉你，在我们实验室里……
Our lab is relatively fast.
我们的实验室速度相对较快。
Our lab only needs to wait a little over 70 days
我们的实验室只需要等待 70 多天。
more than two months
两个多月
Our lab is relatively fast
我们的实验室速度相对较快。
And then
进而
Then when the test results come out
然后等检测结果出来的时候
later, right
稍后，对
he can then match it with his referral letter
然后他可以将其与他的推荐信进行比对。
with these test results can you see the first specialist doctor
凭这些检查结果，您可以去看第一位专科医生吗？
For example, only if it's gynecology will they refer you to a specialist, okay
例如，只有妇科疾病他们才会把你转诊给专科医生，好吗？
You have to schedule another appointment with the specialist doctor
您需要再次预约专科医生。
and also wait in line
还要排队
Right?
正确的？
Okay, three months have passed, and then another three months went by
好吧，三个月过去了，然后又过了三个月。
You've got an appointment with the specialist, yay!
你已经预约了专家，太棒了！
Oh, you're having this stomachache
哦，你肚子疼啊
You're already bleeding heavily
你已经大量出血了。
Well, I think in your case
嗯，我觉得就你的情况而言……
You should get another CT scan of your abdomen.
你应该再做一次腹部 CT 扫描。
Oh I see
我懂了
You go to that whatever hospital to get it done
你去那家医院做这个手术
Hey, is your insurance accepted there? Ah
嘿，你的保险在那里适用吗？啊
Your insurance doesn't cover that.
你的保险不包括这个。
Let me check again like this
让我再这样检查一遍。
Then go ahead and do that again, okay
那就再做一遍，好吗？
You still stayed for three months
你还是待了三个月。
finally came out and said oh
最后他终于开口说了声“哦”。
It seems like you might have uterine fibroids.
你看起来好像患有子宫肌瘤。
Ah, but, but for this surgery we need to take another... uh
啊，但是，但是这次手术我们需要再……呃
Well, let me see
嗯，让我看看
Let me prescribe you some painkillers first.
我先给你开点止痛药。
Because, you see, I have to prescribe
因为，你看，我必须开处方。
I can prescribe medication for you now.
我现在可以给你开药了。
I can prescribe you some birth control pills.
我可以给你开一些避孕药。
because birth control pills regulate estrogen levels
因为避孕药可以调节雌激素水平
can help alleviate this issue for you
可以帮助你缓解这个问题。
Right?
正确的？
This is not even next week.
这甚至还没到下周呢。
real case
真实案例
very real very real
非常真实 非常真实
I couldn't help but laugh when I heard it
听到这话，我忍不住笑了。
so real
太真实了
very real and hard
非常真实且艰难
Because what we have now is this kind of
因为我们现在面临的是这种
There's this trend of natural, eco-friendly, and health-conscious thinking nowadays, right?
现在流行一种天然、环保、注重健康的理念，对吧？
Just like the common overprescription of antibiotics
就像抗生素的滥用一样
I can't prescribe too much of this painkiller for you.
我不能给你开太多这种止痛药。
Right, um, I'll give you one pill a day to start with
好的，嗯，一开始我每天给你开一片药。
I'll give you half a blister pack first
我先给你半包药片。
I'll prescribe you seven pills
我会给你开七粒药。
contraceptive pill
避孕药
Let me give you seven pills first.
我先给你七粒药。
You go back and take it first
你回去先拿走它。
Those seven pills can only be taken for seven days.
这七粒药丸只能服用七天。
That's for the next visit
那是下次来访的事了。
I'm sorry
对不起
approximately one month later
大约一个月后
What about the other 21 days?
剩下的 21 天呢？
Hey, this is not my concern
嘿，这不关我的事。
This is not within my jurisdiction
这不属于我的管辖范围。
Hehe, right?
呵呵，对吧？
Later on, this friend said someone was in critical condition
后来，这位朋友说有人情况危急。
just came back and called me saying, 'Ah,
刚回来就给我打电话说：“啊，
Xiao Zhang and Xiao Li
I'm really in excruciating pain
我真的痛得要命
You see, I've earned so much money in my lifetime, right?
你看，我这辈子赚了很多钱，对吧？
also in my fifties or sixties
我也到了五六十岁。
how come, right
为什么呢，对吧？
This matter is stuck right in my face
这件事就摆在我眼前。
I said, I said, you wait a second
我说，我说，你等一下
Is this the matter?
是这件事吗？
Hey, you give me the report
嘿，你把报告给我。
Come on, let me help you find a... what's it called... Huashan...
来吧，我帮你找找……叫什么来着……华山……
a chief physician from a top-tier hospital somewhere, right
某家顶级医院的首席医师，对吧？
Then deputy chief physician or chief physician might not be available
那么，副主任医师或主任医师可能就无法到岗。
Let me find you an associate chief physician
让我帮你找一位副主任医师
At least a chief physician, right?
至少应该有个主治医师吧？
Look, hey
嘿，看！
Isn't it just a simple surgery?
不就是个小手术吗？
What date is your flight booked for? Ah, September 24th, right?
你订的是哪一天的航班？啊，9 月 24 日，对吧？
Will you arrive in the morning or afternoon on September 24th?
9 月 24 日，您是上午到达还是下午到达？
Arrive in the morning, hey
早上到，好吗？
The flight might be delayed
航班可能会延误
Here's the deal
事情是这样的。
If you can arrive in the morning
如果你能早上到达的话
I'll schedule it for you in the afternoon
我下午会帮你安排。
if you arrive in the afternoon
如果你下午到达。
How about I do it for you the next morning?
不如我明天早上帮你做吧？
Sure
当然
Okay then, let's go ahead.
好的，那我们继续。
late-stage bro bro
后期兄弟兄弟
What you're saying has no impact at all.
你说的话根本没有任何影响。
went to the hospital after work
下班后去了医院
and then had the surgery done in the early morning
然后，他在清晨接受了手术。
discharged the next day
第二天出院
This can be done so incredibly at Li Si's place
在李思家，这简直太不可思议了。
This is simply incomparable, right?
这简直无法相提并论，对吧？
So so so
所以就这样
So this thing is truly, truly evil.
所以这东西真是邪恶至极。
I I I can only say that I, as I as
我只能说，我，作为我，作为
Actually, my stance isn't very neutral either.
实际上，我的立场也并非十分中立。
I think from my perspective
我认为从我的角度来看
To be fair,
公平地说，
The current medical system in Serica is beneficial for the poorest individuals
塞里卡目前的医疗体系对最贫困的人群有利。
it is definitely good
绝对不错
especially in fiscally affluent provinces, right
尤其是在财政富裕的省份，对吧？
You're fully covered by the medical insurance
您的医疗保险涵盖所有费用。
Don't even think about those fancy ideas
别想那些花里胡哨的想法了。
then what's better
那么，哪种更好呢？
Anyway, you just pay less
总之，你只需要少付钱。
Basically, you just need to pay a few hundred or thousand dollars, right?
基本上，你只需要支付几百或几千美元，对吧？
That can provide you with a fairly modern standard
这可以为您提供一个相当现代的标准。
That's not just modern-level
这不仅仅是现代水平
Let me add another mind-blowing example
让我再举一个令人震惊的例子。
I'm not in Guangzhou
我不在广州
Bro, you should know there are quite a few famous doctors in Guangzhou, right?
兄弟，你应该知道广州有不少名医吧？
especially Sun Yat-sen Hospital
特别是孙中山医院
right?
正确的？
If you want to make an appointment with a specialist
如果您想预约专科医生
maybe you can get an appointment with Zhong Nanshan
或许你可以预约钟南山医生。
Nanshan for 1500 bucks, hmm
南山要 1500 块，嗯……
They are indeed practicing.
他们确实在练习。
You're the one seeing patients, right?
你就是负责接诊病人的那位，对吧？
Can you get an appointment?
可以预约吗？
Right, just relying on 3000, right?
对，就靠 3000 这个数，对吧？
And then
进而
Now moving on to the second part
现在进入第二部分
in Seres
在生物中
If you're truly wealthy, right
如果你真的很有钱，对吧？
Because the entire system was not built for you
因为整个系统并非为你而建。
It has already been established for the general public with this free land
它已经通过这块免费土地向公众开放。
free hospitals
免费医院
doctors trained at no cost
免费培训的医生
patients receiving free treatment, right
接受免费治疗的患者，右
has already been established for you
已经为您安排好了
So, even Zhong Nanshan only costs you 1,500 yuan
所以，即使是中南山也只需要 1500 元人民币。
3000 yuan
3000 元
even if you can dig up the person I helped
即使你能找到我帮助过的那个人。
This is already an irregular method.
这本身就是一种不规范的做法。
The most expensive registration fee I've ever heard of
我听过最贵的注册费
I also don't know what this person was thinking
我也不知道这个人当时在想什么。
He insisted on seeing a 94-year-old cancer specialist.
他坚持要见一位 94 岁的癌症专家。
Alright
好吧
you you you want
你，你想
Then I'll help you get it done, okay?
那我来帮你完成这件事，好吗？
I I came up with a solution uh
我想出了一个解决办法。
anyway, found someone and gave him roughly
总之，我找到一个人，然后大致给了他一些钱。
Then can I say this?
那我能这么说吗？
I don't know if I gave 10,000 yuan
我不知道我是否给了 1 万元人民币。
Right?
正确的？
he just got on the list
他刚被列入名单。
It sounds like
听起来像
Of course
当然
Perhaps many people in the Live think this is worth a lot of money, a lot of money?
或许很多现场观众都认为这价值连城，非常非常高？
Think about it again compared to the US, huh, right
再想想跟美国比起来，对吧？
Uh, old buddies
呃，老朋友
I want to ask
我想问
that is if in the West ah
也就是说，如果在西方……
if you encounter a problem that a department can't solve
如果你遇到某个部门无法解决的问题
that is, under the premise that you do not need to pay any additional fees
也就是说，前提是您无需支付任何额外费用。
Would anyone do it without preconditions like we do here
有人会像我们这样不设前提条件就去做吗？
There is no such premise, if it doesn't exist then it doesn't exist
不存在这样的前提，如果它不存在，那就是不存在。
This hypothetical assumption is not an example, there is uh...
这个假设并非示例，而是……
At that time, uh, there was an accident
当时，呃，发生了一起事故。
was a fracture of a bone in the body
是身体某处的骨折。
Brother Lan's medical reimbursement form in China
兰哥在中国的医疗报销单
it's the chest
是箱子
and then without any
然后没有任何
on the premise of paying other fees
在支付其他费用的前提下
directly triggered the alarm
直接触发了警报
the entire hospital was mobilized
整个医院都动员起来了。
It's terrifying, right?
是不是很可怕？
Never mind that for now
暂时先别管这件事。
Get everyone here first
首先把所有人都叫到这里。
joint consultation for severe and critical illnesses
重症和危重症联合会诊
What's needed is, for example, non-specialty departments like orthopedics
例如，我们需要的是像骨科这样的非专科科室。
Internal Medicine
内科
surgery department
外科
to call in all departments that might be related to this condition
召集所有可能与此情况相关的部门。
combined joint rescue
联合救援
that thing
那东西
You'd better not wish for that day to come
你最好别盼着那一天到来。
You generally wouldn't trigger this mechanism
通常情况下，你不会触发这种机制。
usually not near death
通常不会濒临死亡
It's usually the very last moment
通常是最后一刻
snatching lives from the jaws of death
从死神手中夺回生命
Because I, I lived
因为我，我活着
I've been hospitalized
我住院了。
It was because I was hospitalized at the time
那是因为我当时住院了。
I was bored
我很闷
I ran to the emergency room to watch the commotion.
我跑到急诊室去看热闹。
This is really, really not very ethical.
这真的非常非常不道德。
When I was hospitalized
我住院期间
I noticed that as soon as many people come in
我注意到，一旦很多人进来，情况就会发生变化。
that is, you, uh, even some reckless teenagers
也就是说，你，呃，甚至一些鲁莽的青少年
He came in without any explanation of the situation.
他进来时没有对情况做任何解释。
First, save the person's life and then talk about the rest.
首先，救人一命，然后才能谈其他事。
Regardless of the situation
无论情况如何
First, just focus on saving the person, we'll deal with the rest later.
首先，集中精力救人，其他的事情以后再说。
We can discuss the rest later in detail
其余部分我们可以稍后详细讨论。
Well, what I was trying to say earlier is
我刚才想说的是……
it's precisely because of this infrastructure
正是因为有了这种基础设施。
So even if you're considered upper-middle class in China
所以即使你在中国被认为是中上阶层，也未必能成功。
You don't even need to be that wealthy
你甚至不需要很富有。
mid-tier first-tier city middle class
中等水平的一线城市中产阶级
You can actually enjoy world-class services by spending a bit more money yourself.
只要你多花一点钱，就能享受到世界一流的服务。
That is to say, for these two groups of people
也就是说，对于这两类人群而言
actually now it's all
实际上现在这一切都结束了
I think this system is already the optimal one.
我认为这个系统已经是最佳方案了。
If you are just an ordinary person in China with a monthly income
如果你只是中国一个普通的月收入者……
may only be 4,5,6 thousand
可能只有 4、5、6 千。
I will go and see for myself
我会亲自去看看。
Here, at the reinforced shipyard, this is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement bill
这里，在加固的造船厂，这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销账单。
millions
百万
tens of millions to hundreds of millions
数千万到数亿
as long as you haven't reached the point of having more money than you can spend
只要你还没到钱多到花不完的地步。
the point where you could never spend it all
你永远也花不完的点。
before
前
This system is also good for you, yes
是的，这套系统对你也有好处。
I just don't allow people to feel liberated
我就是不允许人们感到自由。
All these people, they must all go abroad
这些人，他们都必须出国。
Oh dear, this is really true, you just haven't encountered such a situation yet
哎呀，这倒是真的，你只是还没遇到过这种情况而已。
Old brother, old brother
老兄，老兄
You should, you're in the industry
你应该这么做，毕竟你身处这个行业。
you should know that during those few years before
你应该知道，在那之前的那几年里……
Some people just have minor illnesses
有些人只是得了些小病。
but just uh just don't believe in Ceres ah
但是，呃，我就是不相信谷神星啊
he had been receiving treatment in China for over a decade without any issues
他在中国接受治疗十多年来一直没有出现任何问题。
but went to Greece
但去了希腊
Every year of treatment forces them to sell their house and car
每过一年，治疗就迫使他们卖掉房子和车。
I will go check it out myself
我会亲自去看看。
Moreover, this is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China
此外，这是纳兰哥在中国的医疗报销单。
I will go and see for myself
我会亲自去看看。
But actually, I have many loves
但实际上，我有很多爱。
Let me give you a very simple example
我举个很简单的例子。
I can even give a very minor illness as an example
我甚至可以举一个轻微疾病的例子。
Shang, strengthen the shipyard
尚，加强造船厂
Don't they all want to have an American baby?
难道他们不都想生个美国宝宝吗？
Shanghai, Jiangnan Shipyard
As everyone knows
众所周知
on, strengthening the shipyard
继续加强造船厂
because pregnancy is a personal choice
因为怀孕是个人选择。
right
正确的
Except for those in the most typical large corporate
除了那些在最典型的大型企业工作的人之外。
Group medical insurance personnel can cover personal liability beyond
团体医疗保险人员可以承担超出个人责任范围的责任。
Here is Brother Nalan's domestic medical reimbursement form from the Jiangnan Shipyard
这是纳兰哥在江南造船厂开具的国内医疗报销单。
I will check it myself
我会亲自核实一下。
What about newborns?
新生儿呢？
For example, if a minor condition like jaundice occurs
例如，如果出现像黄疸这样的轻微疾病
Here is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China from the shipyard.
这是纳兰兄弟在中国造船厂开具的医疗报销单。
You know
你知道
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
That's very common
这很常见。
Here, this is Brother纳兰's medical reimbursement form in China
这是纳兰兄弟在中国的医疗报销单。
He first, right
他首先，没错
Then you have to stay in the ultraviolet room, right or wrong?
那么你就得待在紫外线照射室里，对吧？
Then what about your UV box?
那么你的紫外线杀菌箱呢？
Sigh, it has to be medically certified UV light.
唉，必须是经过医疗认证的紫外线灯。
elephant
大象
with medical certification
附医疗证明
Here, strengthened shipyard, this is Brother Nalan's domestic medical reimbursement form
这里是加固的船厂，这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销单。
right
正确的
Hey
嘿
I know the number is $3000
我知道这个数字是 3000 美元。
Bro, what does this mean
兄弟，这是什么意思？
There's a certified
有认证
Is this so-called Smith specialist not supposed to make money?
这位所谓的史密斯专家难道不应该赚钱吗？
that certified professional
那位认证专业人士
So even using that equipment requires certification, right? Yeah, of course.
所以即使使用那种设备也需要认证，对吧？是的，当然。
He's the one using this equipment.
他就是使用这套设备的人。
Of course
当然
a government hand
政府官员
Oh, I'm doing my postgraduate studies
哦，我正在攻读研究生学位。
Oh dear oh dear
哦，天哪，哦，天哪
Too sweet
太甜了
Listen carefully
仔细听
Here's Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form from 加强造船厂
Here's Brother 纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form from 加强造船厂
But don't forget, it's not up to you when you can get out of treatment
但别忘了，何时结束治疗并非由你决定。
It's not up to you to decide.
这并非由你决定。
For humanitarian purposes
出于人道主义目的
Children lack the capacity to make decisions.
儿童缺乏做决定的能力。
Isn't this something the doctor should decide?
这难道不应该由医生来决定吗？
on, strengthening the shipyard
继续加强造船厂
Haha, right?
哈哈，对吧？
Then staying for 90 days would be a completely normal thing, wouldn't it?
那么待上 90 天就完全正常了，不是吗？
Okay, now take out your calculator
好了，现在拿出你的计算器
How much is $3,000 multiplied by 90 days in dollars?
3000 美元乘以 90 天等于多少美元？
How much is 270,000 dollars multiplied by seven?
27 万美元乘以 7 等于多少？
Oh my god, haha
我的天啊，哈哈
Then it's 100
那么就是 100
Why do we need to multiply 270,000 dollars by seven to convert it to RMB?
为什么我们需要将 27 万美元乘以 7 才能将其转换为人民币？
100 yuan
100 元
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
nearly 2 million
近 200 万
1.89 million
189 万
nearly 2 million, hmm
将近 200 万，嗯。
Shanghai, strengthen the shipyard
上海，加强造船厂建设
Let me read the SC
让我读一下最高法院的判决。
Above, strengthen the shipyard
上方，加强造船厂
There's a joke in the medical industry
医疗界有个笑话
When the intern can't handle it,
当实习生无法胜任时，
might summon their grandmaster to save the day
或许会召唤他们的宗师来力挽狂澜。
There is also one more thing: thank you, Brother J, for the tip.
还有一件事：谢谢 J 兄弟提供的建议。
Click on the damn image
点击那张该死的图片
I'll go check it out myself
我亲自去看看。
searched for a long time
找了很久
I'll go take a look myself
我亲自去看看。
Yes
是的
Is it the picture on the left?
是左边那张图吗？
Well, because, because, because I've been hospitalized before.
嗯，因为，因为，因为我以前住过院。
I would check it myself
我会亲自去查一下。
And at that time, because it was a fracture
当时，因为那是一次骨折。
I will check it myself
我会亲自核实一下。
Did the internal organs show any damage from the impact of the fracture?
骨折冲击是否对内脏器官造成损伤？
I don't even know why
我甚至不知道为什么
and then a whole bunch of doctors came in
然后一大群医生进来了。
and then this examination also checks
然后，这项检查还会检查以下内容。
that touching check
那张触感检查
Only then, at the very end, did they finally feel assured enough to admit me.
直到最后，他们才终于觉得足够放心，录取了我。
Hey hey hey, let me ask you something
嘿嘿嘿，我问你个问题
just bros
只是兄弟
If such a situation occurs
如果出现这种情况
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
Well first of all, there needs to be an authoritative institution
首先，需要一个权威机构。
This institution itself must have an adequate number of doctors
该机构本身必须拥有足够数量的医生
this premise
这个前提
on strengthening the shipyard, this is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form
关于加强船厂建设，这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销单
I will go and see for myself
我会亲自去看看。
I remember Mayo, I specialize in treating cancer.
我记得梅奥诊所，我专攻癌症治疗。
I'll go see it myself.
我打算亲自去看一看。
What is he specialized in treating?
他擅长治疗什么疾病？
His starting point is entirely different.
他的出发点完全不同。
Your hospital might not necessarily have a general practice department
您的医院可能没有全科医疗部门。
Oh
哦
Oh, in his hospital, it's not like us
哦，在他住的医院里，情况跟我们不一样。
Here is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form from the shipyard
这是纳兰兄弟从造船厂开具的国内医疗报销单。
That is because what
那是因为什么
Because this hospital was originally established by some wealthy individuals
因为这家医院最初是由一些富裕人士创办的。
something specifically invested in
专门投资的东西
because the hospital itself was custom-built
因为医院本身是专门定制建造的。
It does not serve the people
它对人民没有好处。
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
it serves the people
它服务于人民。
And then the second point is that there needs to be an initiator, uh
第二点是，需要有一个发起人，嗯。
Here is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form from the shipyard.
这是 Brother 纳兰从船厂获得的国内医疗报销单。
But but I remember in our insurance service
但是，我记得在我们的保险服务中
Above is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China from the strengthened shipyard.
以上是纳兰兄弟在中国加固的造船厂开具的医疗报销单。
You can initiate this thing.
你可以启动这个程序。
I will check it myself
我会亲自核实一下。
On the reinforcement shipyard, this is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement form
在加固船厂，这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销单
36 days in the ICU
在重症监护室住了 36 天
two days in a row
连续两天
On, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
It seems the report was completed with over 40.
这份报告似乎已经完成了 40 多个人。
Shanghai, strengthen shipyard
上海，加强造船厂建设
I don't know the exact figure
我不知道确切数字。
Anyway, my dad mentioned it was like over 40.
总之，我爸说大概超过 40 了。
Let me show you all
让我来给你们全部展示一下。
Is it still
还是
Let me read it for you
我来读给你听。
American doctors
美国医生
I will go see for myself
我会亲自去看看。
Every year, every year, every year, they receive patients
每年，每年，每年，他们都会接收病人。
Ah, there's no data.
啊，没有数据。
That is, countless surgeons, 320 to 820 cases a year.
也就是说，无数外科医生每年要进行 320 到 820 例手术。
Psychiatrists 50~170
精神科医生 50~170
Here is Brother Nalan's domestic medical reimbursement slip at the strengthened shipyard
这是纳兰兄弟在加固造船厂开具的国内医疗报销单。
300 to 450 a year
每年 300 至 450
Um, a year
一年
So if this shutdown incident happens
所以如果这次停工事件发生
Here is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form from a domestic shipyard.
这是纳兰兄弟从国内造船厂获得的医疗报销单。
Haha, fifty or sixty million people
哈哈，五六千万人
So now ACACA is now yes
所以现在 ACACA 的答案是肯定的。
And also, this is the AACA
还有，这是 AACA
I will go check it out myself
我会亲自去看看。
Here is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China from the strengthened shipyard.
这是纳兰兄弟在中国加固的造船厂开具的医疗报销单。
I've seen some families of four
我见过一些四口之家。
The parents have to pay 42,100 yuan in annual insurance premiums for their two children.
这对父母每年需要为他们的两个孩子缴纳 42100 元的保险费。
Shang, strengthen the shipyard
尚，加强造船厂
Just think about this expense
想想这笔开销。
from 2000 a month to 42,000 a year
从每月 2000 到每年 42000
Can he afford it?
他买得起吗？
He can't afford it, hmm
他买不起，嗯。
absolutely unaffordable
完全负担不起
It's a matter of life and death
这是生死攸关的事。
Here, strengthening the shipyard. This is Brother Nalan's domestic medical reimbursement form.
这里，正在加固船厂。这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销单。
That is not just 16 million
那可不仅仅是 1600 万。
he has 60 million
他有 6000 万
covered the costs for approximately over 70 million people
涵盖了大约 7000 多万人的费用
There are also nearly 10 million illegal immigrants among them.
其中还有近 1000 万非法移民。
Illegal immigrants are purely consuming this money
非法移民完全是在挥霍这些钱。
Additionally, strengthen the shipyard
此外，加强造船厂建设
you know what I mean
你知道我的意思
Here, strengthening the shipyard is Brother纳兰’s domestic medical reimbursement form
这里，加强造船厂建设是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销表格
their housing
他们的住房
I'll go check it out myself
我亲自去看看。
It was Trump who abolished it
是特朗普废除了它。
It is regarded as a welfare benefit by the middle class.
中产阶级将其视为一项福利。
Just think about it
仔细想想
In November, because of the renewal of health insurance in the United States
11 月，由于美国医疗保险的续期
roughly from October to the end of November
大致从十月到十一月底
I'm renewing my health insurance for the next year
我正在续保下一年的健康保险。
There are a few things in November
十一月有几件事。
The ACA is about to be terminated, right?
《平价医疗法案》（ACA）即将终止，对吗？
food stamps
食品券
Here, strengthening the shipyard is Brother纳兰's medical reimbursement form in China.
在这里，加强造船厂建设是 Brother 纳兰在中国的医疗报销表格。
I will check it myself
我会亲自核实一下。
Above, strengthening the shipyard, this is Brother Nalan's domestic medical reimbursement form
以上是加固船厂的部分，这是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销单。
basically consistent
基本一致
which is 42 million people
也就是 4200 万人
no food stamps
没有食品券
But the freight charges are definitely still being collected now.
但目前运费肯定还在收取。
right
正确的
So the shipping industry's national fortunes are in disorder.
因此，航运业的命运岌岌可危。
The port of Seattle has been completely devastated.
西雅图港已彻底损毁。
and strengthen the shipyard
并加强造船厂
and then uh because of deporting illegal immigrants
然后，呃，因为遣返非法移民
That Old A has talked about it many times before
老 A 以前多次谈到过这件事。
illegal immigrants
非法移民
many demanding jobs
许多高要求的工作
either in the catering industry
无论是在餐饮业
or slaughtering
或屠宰
or agriculture
或农业
I'll go check it out myself
我亲自去看看。
maintaining urban operations
维持城市运转
the urban underclass, um, okay
城市底层阶级，嗯，好吧
And then these things of yours
然后还有你的这些东西
If it happens to coincide with, as everyone knows, November being Thanksgiving
如果恰好与 11 月感恩节重合，众所周知，11 月是感恩节。
December is Christmas
十二月是圣诞节
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
and Halloween
以及万圣节
Has it passed?
已经过去了吗？
On, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
It's almost over
快结束了
On, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
in our neighborhood
在我们社区
It seems that this thing hasn't been prepared for the children yet
看来这东西还没准备好给孩子们用。
but anyway what
不过话说回来，什么？
That is to say, if these few things are stacked together
也就是说，如果把这几样东西放在一起比较……
Then perhaps out of 300 million people, 160 million won't be affected.
那么，在 3 亿人口中，或许有 1.6 亿人不会受到影响。
No problem
没问题
it means there's that company
这意味着有那家公司
Here is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China, let's strengthen the shipyard
这是纳兰兄弟在中国的医疗报销单，让我们加强造船厂建设吧。
The remaining bit is completely different
剩下的部分则完全不同。
on, strengthening the shipyard
继续加强造船厂
Because there are still 20 million illegal immigrants.
因为还有 2000 万非法移民。
Damn, it's really eating away at everything, absolutely nothing left
该死，它真的把一切都吞噬殆尽，什么都没剩下。
And just as Lao Yi mentioned earlier
正如老毅之前提到的那样。
This one is also not easy to cut off
这个也不容易切掉。
once it's cut off
一旦被切断
it will be troublesome later
以后会很麻烦。
I will go check it myself
我本人会去查看。
Damn, someone's gonna go to extremes soon.
糟了，看来有人很快就要走极端了。
I've already collected many bodies these past two days.
过去两天我已经收集了很多尸体。
The temperature is getting lower and lower
气温越来越低
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
The humidity is getting higher and higher
湿度越来越高了。
The rain is becoming more frequent
雨越来越频繁了。
Someone is bound to crack first
总会有人第一个崩溃的。
Fortunately, energy prices have been low these two days.
幸运的是，这两天的能源价格一直很低。
But then again
但话又说回来……
Electricity prices in the US are rising again
美国电价再次上涨
Electricity prices in the U.S. are now fluctuating between rising and falling.
美国的电价目前呈现波动趋势，时而上涨，时而下跌。
Electricity prices in the U.S. are now rising outrageously.
美国的电价现在正以惊人的速度上涨。
I will check it myself
我会亲自核实一下。
My electricity bill has increased.
我的电费账单上涨了。
Our average annual electricity bill now
我们现在的平均年度电费
The average increase is around fourteen to fourteen percent.
平均增幅约为 14%至 14%。
On average, that's not too bad, is it?
平均而言，这还算不错，对吧？
That's on average
这是平均水平
and it must be calculated based on 202
而且必须根据 202 进行计算
Shanghai Jiangnan Shipyard
By last year, the average annual rate was 14%
截至去年，平均年利率为 14%。
But in fact, it increased by 22% last year.
但事实上，去年增长了 22%。
It's just an average, you know.
这只是个平均值而已。
Last year it was 22%
去年是 22%。
This year it's basically heading for over 25%
今年基本上要超过 25%了
Thanks to Xinfengzhitian
Brother Da Gan
达干哥
I'll check it myself
我会亲自检查一下。
Discharged in July
七月出院
47,000
｛1001｝
After reimbursement, it's 11,000
报销后，是 11,000。
My medical insurance card has 7,000
我的医疗保险卡有 7000 元
In the end, I only had to pay 3,000.
最后，我只需要支付 3000 元。
on, strengthen the shipyard
继续加强造船厂建设
That's why there's now an expectation saying
这就是为什么现在人们期望说……
Perhaps Trump is about to immediately taco on apex
或许特朗普马上就要在巅峰时期大展拳脚了。
Let me think about it, yeah yeah
让我想想，嗯嗯
Actually, they don't care whether he collapses or not
事实上，他们并不关心他是否会倒下。
This matter is definitely beyond saving
这件事已经无可挽回了。
Here, strengthening the shipyard, this is Brother Nalan's medical reimbursement form in China.
这里，加强造船厂建设，这是纳兰兄弟在中国的医疗报销单。
His food stamps and everything have all been restored to your logistics
他的食品券和其他所有东西都已恢复到你们物流部门的记录中。
Go, strengthen the shipyard
去，加强造船厂建设
There's no way that would be in time.
绝对来不及。
Thanks to Brother Zhen Dasha
感谢甄达沙兄弟
Come on, strengthen the shipyard
加油，加强造船厂建设！
European and American health insurance is too shady
欧美医疗保险太不透明了。
leading to skyrocketing costs
导致成本飙升
On the other hand, strengthen the shipyard
另一方面，加强造船厂建设
cannot afford medical treatment
负担不起医疗费用
resulting in an increasing number of Gundams
导致高达的数量不断增加
while Gundam can still be recycled for more uses
高达模型仍然可以回收利用，用于更多用途。
using the damn thing
用那玩意儿
Here, strengthening the shipyard is Brother纳兰's domestic medical reimbursement bill
这里，加强造船厂建设就是纳兰兄弟的国内医疗报销账单。
No wonder the U.S. population remains stagnant despite a continuous surge in immigration
难怪尽管移民数量持续激增，美国人口却依然停滞不前。
the overall population remains relatively stagnant
总体人口数量保持相对稳定。
It's completely inhumane
这完全不人道。
I'm still going to share this picture, um, yes, let me tell you
我还是要分享这张照片，嗯，是的，让我告诉你。
I'm really grateful today that Lao Wei allowed me to speak.
今天我非常感激老伟允许我发言。
Today is my first time being a guest here, um
今天是我第一次来这里做客人，嗯。
There's actually a problem here that
这里实际上存在一个问题：
Many of my American classmates told me at the time
当时我的许多美国同学都告诉我这一点。
Now, but it was much later that I gradually came to understand.
但过了很久我才逐渐明白。
Actually, for the vast majority of Americans
事实上，对于绝大多数美国人来说
I will go and see for myself
我会亲自去看看。
I think people back home probably haven't experienced much of this yet
我觉得家乡的人们可能还没怎么经历过这些。
but in first-tier cities
但在一线城市
especially in second-tier cities
尤其是在二线城市
Perhaps it also includes the notion that everyone has
或许它也包含了每个人都拥有的这种观念。
like when grandparents pass away and leave behind a house
比如祖父母去世后留下一栋房子
Does this kind of thought exist?
这种想法真的存在吗？
Is it common
常见吗？
It should be quite common in the domestic market, right?
这在国内市场应该很常见吧？
Ah, it's quite normal
啊，这很正常。
Let me tell you all, I mean
让我来告诉你们所有人，我的意思是
Go ahead and strengthen the shipyard, this is the N/A
请继续加强造船厂建设，这是不适用的。
many so-called second-generation rich kids in Guangzhou
广州有很多所谓的富二代
how come it's just so simple
为什么就这么简单呢？
can't do anything
什么都做不了
but they have a piece of land
但他们拥有一块土地。
There has been demolition
已经进行了拆除
let alone the rental income
更别提租金收入了。
In those situations, I would say even if the grandparents were workers
在这种情况下，即使祖父母是劳动者，我也会说……
at least they got a house
至少他们得到了一套房子。
A house can be sold for around 1 million yuan no matter what.
无论如何，房子都能卖到 100 万元左右。
right
正确的
Oh no no no, it depends on the location
哦不不不，这取决于地点。
Ah
啊
No no no no, that's not the case
不不不不，不是这样的。
Bro, if you understand his grandparents
兄弟，如果你了解他的祖父母……
If they were former frontline state-owned enterprise workers
如果他们是以前国有企业一线员工。
The location of his house would definitely not be bad
他家的位置肯定不错。
and might even possibly
甚至有可能
and often more than one property
而且通常不止一处房产
Yeah yeah yeah
对对对对
even if it's just one house
即使只是一栋房子
the best-case scenario
最佳情况
We ordinary people also need to consider that China has many second-tier cities, right?
我们普通人也需要考虑到，中国有很多二线城市，对吧？
People often call me an appendage in the group chat.
在群聊里，人们经常叫我“附属物”。
It's because I don't take these situations into account
这是因为我没有考虑到这些情况。
I am considering these situations
我正在考虑这些情况。
But why doesn't the United States have it?
但为什么美国没有呢？
The inheritance tax is terrifying.
遗产税太可怕了。
The estate tax is just one aspect
遗产税只是其中一个方面。
First of all, right
首先，没错
Back when grandparents were in their prime
想当年祖父母正值壮年的时候
bought that house
买下了那栋房子
have to pay property taxes for the house
必须缴纳房屋房产税
right
正确的
have to pay property taxes for the house
必须缴纳房屋房产税
Then you have to send your child to the school district, right?
那么你就得把孩子送到学区去上学，对吧？
All these should help pay for the children's college tuition
这些钱应该都能帮助支付孩子们的大学学费。
All these things should be taken care of, right?
这些事情都应该得到妥善处理，对吧？
Then what happens
然后会发生什么？
Then the children all go to college
然后孩子们都上大学。
Would he feel that the house is a bit empty like an empty nest
他会不会觉得房子有点空荡荡的，像个空巢一样？
the elderly feel empty and lonely
老年人感到空虚和孤独
It's too big to live in now, right?
现在住起来太大了，对吧？
living in a two or three hundred square meter house
住在两三百平方米的房子里
can't live in two
不能住在两个地方
Why should I pay so much property tax for no reason?
我为什么要无缘无故缴纳这么多房产税？
A large portion of the property tax goes towards education, right?
房产税的大部分都用于教育，对吧？
Then I'll just downsize a bit more
那我再缩小一下规模吧。
Then I'll downsize a bit more
Alas, my old partner is gone
唉，我的老搭档已经不在了。
Let me switch to a smaller one
我换个小点的。
In the end, in the end, they had to move into a nursing home
最后，最后，他们不得不搬进养老院。
In the end, I'll just live in a nursing home.
最终，我可能只能住在养老院了。
There will still be blind spots in the front and back.
前方和后方仍然会存在盲区。
1shit and die, right
1shit and die，对吧
This term is definitely heard in the United States
这个词在美国肯定有人听过。
called eating and die
被称为吃和死
And then it's not, hey
然后就不是这样了，嘿
Let me interject
让我插一句
what does this mean
这是什么意思？
I don't understand
我不明白
Go eat shit
去吃屎吧
Then you just die there, you old geezer, right?
然后你就死在那儿了，你这老家伙，对吧？
That's right, being blocked and spamming coins, spamming coins, huh?
没错，被封号然后疯狂刷金币，疯狂刷金币，是吗？
Isn't this just landing
这不就是着陆吗？
just eat, shit, and wait to die
吃喝拉撒，等死就完了
just these three things
仅此三件事
Eat, shit, and wait to die, hmm
吃喝拉撒，等死，嗯。
You have nothing else to do
你无事可做
And then all the money, you think how expensive labor is in the U.S.
然后还有所有的钱，想想美国的劳动力成本有多高。
How expensive is the land rent in the United States?
美国的土地租金有多贵？
Do you think nursing homes in the U.S. are cheap, right?
你觉得美国的养老院很便宜，对吗？
You end up arriving naked and leaving naked
你最终赤身裸体地来，也赤身裸体地离开。
leave with nothing
空手而归
being completely exploited by society leaves nothing behind
被社会彻底剥削，最终一无所有。
Your grandchildren won't inherit anything from you
你的孙辈不会继承你的任何东西。
Yes
是的
those so-called Chuanbei Y, right
那些所谓的川北 Y，对吧
is that the family really has a considerable amount of property
这个家庭确实拥有相当数量的财产。
can be passed down from generation to generation
可以代代相传
and often have already
而且通常已经有了
Now it is commonly passed down through trust forms.
现在通常通过信托形式传承。
That is indeed a minority, but it does exist.
这确实是少数情况，但确实存在。
Many of my former classmates were like this
我以前的很多同学都是这样的。
But such cases are a minority in society as a whole
但就整个社会而言，这类案例只占少数。
the vast majority of people are
绝大多数人
will be completely, utterly, and thoroughly abandoned by the entire market economy society
将被整个市场经济社会彻底、完全、彻底地抛弃。
won't be burned to ashes
不会被烧成灰烬
In China, even if you're extremely poor, right?
在中国，即使你非常贫穷，对吧？
If your grandparents are from the countryside
如果你的祖父母来自农村
has a homestead
拥有一处宅基地
Well, well, there are also guests outside who say you can go back home and farm.
嗯，嗯，外面也有客人说你可以回家务农。
You can really go back to farming
你真的可以重操旧业了。
That's right
这是正确的
And if you're a worker,
如果你是一名工人，
you were assigned a house back then
当时你被分配了一套房子。
WeChat payment
微信支付
Many people think I'm already very poor in China.
很多人认为我在中国已经很穷了。
I only have a few thousand yuan in salary
我只有几千元工资。
My grandparents are just ordinary people.
我的祖父母只是普通人。
Oh my
哦，我的
Look at America
看看美国
nothing at all
什么都没有
Let me read the SC
让我读一下最高法院的判决。
Thank you Puppet
谢谢你，木偶
Nothingness, my grand prize
虚无，我的终极大奖
Will Lao Yi go back for the New Year?
老义会回去过年吗？
Enjoy delicious food to your heart's content
尽情享用美味佳肴
I can't go back for the New Year.
我回不去了，过不了新年。
I have to finish my studies
我必须完成学业
Thanks to Brother Finny for the reward
感谢芬尼兄弟的奖励
Here in Serica, they keep talking about cutting medical insurance costs
在塞里卡，他们一直在讨论削减医疗保险费用。
divert patients
分流病人
alleviate the outpatient pressure on top-tier hospitals
缓解顶级医院的门诊压力
So what is the solution?
那么解决方案是什么？
Strengthen the construction of primary medical institutions and infrastructure
加强基层医疗机构和基础设施建设
I'm not sure about other places
我不确定其他地方的情况。
Jiangsu must also achieve
江苏省也必须实现
every township health center and community health service center is fully equipped with
每个乡镇卫生中心和社区卫生服务中心都配备了齐全的……
CT, DR, color ultrasound, and electrocardiogram
CT、DR、彩色超声和心电图
blood tests
血液检查
blood tests and such
血液检查等等
Basic biochemistry tests are all done in-house
基础生化检测均在院内完成。
Unable to perform, sent to external laboratory
无法进行检测，已送至外部实验室。
and then comprehensively reduce prices
然后全面降低价格
From examinations to lab tests to medications, complete localization of production
从体检、实验室检测到药物治疗，生产完全本地化。
slashed prices
价格大幅下降
When I first started working
我刚开始工作的时候
In 2017, a CT scan cost over 200
2017 年，一次 CT 扫描的费用超过 200 美元。
close to 300
接近 300
Now the price has been slashed
现在价格已经大幅下调。
halved to 150
减半至 150
still a tier-3 hospital's remotely prescribed medication
仍然是三级医院远程开具的处方药
The chronic disease medication costs just a few cents per pill.
这种慢性病药物每片只需几美分。
So cheap that ordinary people doubt its effectiveness
价格如此低廉，以至于普通人都怀疑它的有效性。
Thank you to Xiaofeng Han and Brother Lao for the reward, let me show you all
感谢韩晓峰和老哥的奖励，让我来给大家展示一下。
My father was treated for cancer in Guangzhou in 2024.
2024 年，我父亲在广州接受了癌症治疗。
the largest expense among them
其中最大的一笔开支
clearly reflects the extent of the government's investment and support in critical illness medical coverage
这清楚地反映了政府在重大疾病医疗保险方面的投入和支持力度。
Except for some examinations and special personnel services
除某些考试和特殊人事服务外
It really tries to minimize costs for ordinary people.
它确实努力为普通民众降低成本。
Because currently in China, the main focus is actually on examinations
因为目前在中国，主要的关注点实际上是考试。
Well, actually, once the examination is done, everything will be easier to handle.
其实，一旦考试结束，一切都会更容易处理。
After the examination, you will find that once it is clearly identified
检查之后，你会发现一旦它被明确识别出来。
is a problem
这是一个问题
Right now it's because the cost control has gone too far
目前的问题在于成本控制过度了。
so there's a bit of overcorrection uh
所以有点矫枉过正了。
I might have heard of something called DRG-based healthcare reform.
我可能听说过一种叫做基于 DRG 的医疗改革。
This is a policy imported from the United States
这是从美国引进的一项政策。
It makes doctors oh
它让医生们哦
I don't know what can be said about this
我不知道对此还能说什么。
Can't say, can't say
不能说，不能说
Anyway, the result is that sometimes there are certain choices
总之，结果是，有时确实存在某些选择。
some treatment options
一些治疗方案
the doctor will tell you
医生会告诉你
unless you go to those self-pay places
除非你去那些自费的地方。
those places and so on
那些地方等等
This comes back to you again
这又回到了你身上。
So this is why middle-class and above individuals
所以这就是为什么中产阶级及以上人士
You should damn well pay out of pocket
你理应自掏腰包。
Please go for the self-paid special consultation
请前往自费专项咨询处咨询。
only 400 yuan
仅需 400 元
800 yuan
800 元
1500 yuan is enough to get an appointment with Zhong Nanshan
花 1500 元就能约到钟南山医生。
what else do you want
你还想要什么？
Then let's take a look at
那么我们来看看……
You should not, you should not compete with the poor for money
你不应该，你不应该和穷人争夺金钱。
Let me show you
让我来给你展示一下。
How many people went missing in the US this year?
今年美国有多少人失踪？
Ah, this year in the US, no fewer than 530,000 people have gone missing.
啊，今年美国已有不少于 53 万人失踪。
Great
伟大的
530,000 people are missing in the United States
美国有 53 万人失踪
53 legal residents
53 名合法居民
530,000 missing legal residents
53 万失踪的合法居民
Not bad
不错
Ah
啊
at its peak
在其巅峰时期
In 1997 alone, 980,000 people went missing.
仅在 1997 年，就有 98 万人失踪。
Yes, it's the legal population
是的，这是法定人口。
excluding the illegal ones, bros
兄弟们，非法的除外。
Although I think the decline in missing persons
虽然我认为失踪人口数量的下降是原因之一
It's because the statistical capability has declined.
这是因为统计能力下降了。
This is in the Yellow Register
这在黄皮书登记册里。
the registered population
登记人口
First of all, the missing person must be a legal resident
首先，失踪人员必须是合法居民。
and someone has to report him missing
必须有人报告他失踪。
on record
有记录
Only then can he be considered a legitimate missing person
只有这样，他才能被认定为合法失踪人员。
How many illegal immigrants go missing each year?
每年有多少非法移民失踪？
That stuff isn't properly counted anyway
那些东西本来就没被正确统计过。
WeChat payment received 30 yuan
微信支付收到 30 元
Someone said it's that scary
有人说它很可怕。
Yeah, it's really that scary
是啊，真的太可怕了。
Thanks to NEOK
感谢 NEOK
Brother Hua tipped
华哥小费
Let me take a look
让我看看
Anchor, I have quite a bit to say
安克尔，我有很多话要说。
Let me explain bit by bit
让我一点一点地解释。
First and foremost
首先，也是最重要的
This afternoon my younger brother told me
今天下午，我弟弟告诉我
He saw something online
他在网上看到了一些东西。
It's an article from Beijing Daily
这是《北京日报》的一篇文章。
The general idea is that we don't need to envy winning Nobel Prizes or the like.
总的来说，我们不必羡慕获得诺贝尔奖之类的奖项。
Then some creatures appeared in the Douyin comment section
然后抖音评论区出现了一些生物。
Then you say Serica can't see the grapes and calls them sour
然后你说塞丽卡看不见葡萄，就说它们是酸的。
sour grapes
酸葡萄
My brother's thinking was somewhat swayed by some comments.
我哥哥的想法受到了一些评论的影响。
I scolded my brother at that time
那时我责骂了我哥哥
I mean, at your current stage, you shouldn't be looking at this kind of stuff.
我的意思是，以你目前的阶段，你不应该关注这类事情。
Reading too much of this stuff can mess with your mind
读太多这类东西会扰乱你的心智
My younger brother is now in his first year of high school
我弟弟现在读高一。
It's a time when his thoughts are quite unstable.
那段时间他的情绪很不稳定。
I think this older brother should do something
我觉得这位哥哥应该做点什么。
Otherwise, his mindset will become increasingly unstable.
否则，他的精神状态会变得越来越不稳定。
Yes, yes
是的，是的
I totally agree
我完全同意
It was my second term
那是我的第二个任期。
Me too me too
我也是我也是
The second thing
第二件事
A few days ago I saw Shi Wen Jian Wen Wu and a YouTuber called Jian Hu, um,
几天前我看到了石文健文武和一个叫健虎的油管博主，嗯，
The Jianhu Talk YouTuber discusses the issue of water scarcity in U.S. agriculture.
建虎谈 YouTuber 讨论了美国农业缺水问题。
I find that compared to issues like healthcare
我发现，与医疗保健等问题相比，这个问题显得尤为重要。
Uncle Sam's water issue is even more
山姆大叔的水资源问题更加严重。
their wheat and stuff
他们的麦子之类的东西
are all established near water sources
所有这些建筑都建在水源附近
Good lord
我的天哪
he's just special
他就是那么特别。
His wheat cultivation is consistently carried out in water-scarce areas.
他一直都在缺水地区种植小麦。
And according to the analysis by these two UPloders
根据这两位上传者的分析
Do you know why a lot of American agriculture
你知道为什么美国农业很多
Can it only be planted in water-scarce areas?
它只能种植在缺水地区吗？
because the areas with water were occupied by the industrial capitalists of the previous generation
因为有水的地方都被上一代的工业资本家占据了。
industrial capitalists occupy the best locations
工业资本家占据了最好的地段。
Agriculture cannot sustain itself, hmm
农业无法自我维持，嗯。
and according to the analysis by these two up
根据这两位人士的分析，
The U.S. water crisis is projected to peak in 20 years.
美国水危机预计将在 20 年后达到顶峰。
but I haven't seen any government
但我还没见过任何政府
Are there any countermeasures for the water shortage crisis currently experienced in the United States?
美国目前面临水资源短缺危机，有哪些应对措施？
The United States is not short of water
美国并不缺水。
Because, because, because the water in the U.S. has already been controlled
因为，因为，因为美国的水资源已经被控制了。
The vast majority of water sources in the U.S. are privately owned.
美国绝大多数水源为私人所有。
and you can almost trace it back to 4-5 water utility groups
而且几乎可以追溯到 4-5 个自来水公司。
Alright
好吧
is basically all the water in the United States
基本上就是美国所有的水
basically controlled by four or five water utility groups
基本上由四五个水务集团控制。
water resources across the United States
美国各地的水资源
But I don't have it
但我没有。
I don't know how the United States will solve
我不知道美国将如何解决这个问题。
their future water scarcity issue
他们未来面临的水资源短缺问题
I heard they have some kind of underground aquifer
我听说他们那里有某种地下含水层。
may be completely depleted in 20 years
可能在 20 年内完全耗尽
these per capita usage
这些人均使用量
Especially these people's water usage habits are particularly
尤其是这些人的用水习惯特别……
That place in California also grows a huge amount of
加州那个地方也盛产……
water-intensive crops
需水量大的作物
especially those leaves
尤其是那些叶子
Can I request a song?
我可以点歌吗？
Sure
当然
Let me first explain to everyone
首先让我向大家解释一下。
When it comes to U.S. agriculture
就美国农业而言
Many of its agricultural states are actually in water-scarce zones, alas.
可惜的是，该国许多农业州实际上都位于缺水地区。
WeChat payment received 30 yuan
微信支付收到 30 元
It requires a large number of farm laborers, farm laborers.
它需要大量的农场工人，农场工人。
Why does the US have so many illegal immigrants
为什么美国有这么多非法移民？
To a large extent, it's because
很大程度上是因为
American agriculture requires massive manual labor and large-scale machinery
美国农业需要大量的人工和大型机械。
working in coordination to get the job done
协同合作完成工作
he has for illegal immigrants
他对非法移民有这样的看法
The demand for such slave-like labor at the bottom is virtually unlimited.
对底层这种奴隶般劳动力的需求几乎是无限的。
Do you understand?
你明白吗？
Open your mouth
张开嘴
Let me know who I am
让我知道我是谁
Defeat someone who says
打败一个说
Why does the US need so many illegal immigrants
为什么美国需要这么多非法移民？
Look at all the farming states in America
看看美国所有的农业州。
all agricultural and farming states
所有农业州
Due to water shortages and large-scale operations
由于缺水和大规模作业
Their demand for slave labor is virtually limitless.
他们对奴隶劳动力的需求几乎是无限的。
Boundless silence tells me what to do
无垠的寂静告诉我该怎么做
Thanks to Brother Tan Xiaomiao Pets for the tip
感谢谭晓苗宠物兄弟提供的信息
Listening to pure support for the UPloader in the Live
在现场聆听对上传者的纯粹支持
It's nothing, really.
没什么。
OK thanks bro
好的，谢谢兄弟
Blessed at the foot of my hometown
在我的家乡脚下，我感到无比幸福
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
540,000 legal residents go missing each year.
每年有 54 万合法居民失踪。
530,000 ah
530,000
Lira's day will be white silk
莉拉的婚礼当天将以白色丝绸为主题。
how many serfs
有多少农奴
were directly killed by American plantation owners
直接被美国种植园主杀害
That was terrifying.
太可怕了。
Thanks to Brother Bacon for the generous tip
感谢培根兄弟慷慨的小费
This video watermark
此视频水印
Not sure if it's a red SC.
不确定是不是红色 SC。
This can't be put here
这里放不下这个。
I don't have the qualifications for this
我不具备这份工作的资格。
Brother, if you're afraid of getting into trouble
兄弟，如果你害怕惹上麻烦的话。
You can directly start watching Minister Li's video from the 55-second mark
您可以直接从李部长视频的第 55 秒开始观看。
The expression was very serious at first
起初他的表情非常严肃。
Later, when talking about the tough stance of the American side, he could hardly hold back.
后来，在谈到美方的强硬立场时，他几乎无法掩饰自己的不满。
I'll forward it to the group chat
我会把它转发到群聊里。
I can't broadcast this with the logo
我无法播放带有徽标的内容。
There's a station logo
这里有车站标志。
I can't show this, this will get me directly shot
我不能把这个给别人看，这会让我直接被枪毙。
and didn't even tell me
他甚至都没告诉我。
Hey, I'm asking that, hey, the guy in the Live
嘿，我问的是，嘿，现场直播的那个人。
Let me ask you another question
我还想问你一个问题。
It's NO NO name, ah ah NO NO name
是 NO NO 名字，啊啊 NO NO 名字
Bro, uh, as for me, it's about the medication effectiveness again
兄弟，呃，对我来说，关键还是药物的疗效。
Can this issue be adjusted
这个问题可以调整吗？
You said it was originally like this
你说它原本是这样的
sometimes you might find that the Greek key
有时你可能会发现希腊钥匙
It's particularly strong
它特别强。
Could this be divided into two aspects
这是否可以分为两个方面？
On one hand,
一方面，
ALEX must also know that the dosage itself is different, right?
亚历克斯肯定也知道剂量本身是不一样的，对吧？
In many cases, the dosage in China might only be 15.
在中国，很多情况下剂量可能只有 15。
they give a dose of 200, right
他们给的剂量是 200，对吧。
is 200G
是 200G
Do I not know first?
难道我事先不知道吗？
You can search it up
你可以搜一下。
Let me first say
首先我想说的是……
Look at what's written on the waistband
看看腰带上写的是什么。
Let me tell you all
让我来告诉你们一切
Chinese medicine is generally content, which is ox
中医一般认为牛是合适的。
is the extended-release form of OxyContin
是奥施康定的缓释剂型。
The U.S. doesn't operate this way
美国并非如此运作。
The US starts with the maximum dose right away
美国一开始就使用最大剂量。
Max m charge
最大电荷
Tsk
啧
Got it
知道了
Right
正确的
First of all, the dosage allowed for everyone
首先，剂量适合所有人。
used to it
习惯了
it's different
情况不同。
For instance, in China, the dosages might be 10, 15, or 30 milligrams.
例如，在中国，剂量可能是 10 毫克、15 毫克或 30 毫克。
the same medication, right
同样的药物，对吧？
In the US, the price might start at 150, 200, or 250.
在美国，价格可能从 150、200 或 250 起。
This will make you feel
这会让你感觉
the potency is different
效力不同
But every medicine has its side effects
但每种药物都有副作用
for the liver and kidneys, right
对肝脏和肾脏来说，没错。
The impact on certain things is different.
对某些方面的影响则有所不同。
Let's say this is one side of the issue, the A side
假设这是问题的一方面，即 A 面
Then there's the B-side of the issue
然后还有这个问题的另一面。
Well, actually nowadays many of these active ingredients
实际上，如今很多这类活性成分
itself
本身
Everyone finds it not difficult to produce after discovering this, right?
发现这一点后，大家都觉得生产并不难，对吧？
However, the purity and impurities of the active ingredients
然而，活性成分的纯度和杂质
The effect of your sustained-release agent is too poor.
你的缓释剂效果太差。
Because you have different prices
因为你们的价格不同
It might be different, right?
或许情况会有所不同，对吧？
so I I I can't simply say
所以，我不能简单地说
is this one better or that one
这个好还是那个好？
But generally speaking, the more choices you have, the better, which is certainly fine.
但总的来说，选择越多越好，这当然无可厚非。
For me, the ideal situation is the ideal situation is
对我来说，理想的情况就是……
you can go to the best in the country
你可以去全国最好的学校。
when you can see a doctor and buy all the medicines worldwide
当你可以看医生并购买全世界所有的药品时
This is theoretically the most perfect.
理论上这是最完美的。
and when necessary, you can even go to the United States for something
必要时，你甚至可以去美国做某事。
those so-called online
那些所谓的网络用户
online multidisciplinary consultation, right
在线多学科会诊，没错
So this is theoretically the most perfect
所以，从理论上讲，这是最完美的。
But it requires money.
但这需要钱。
This healthcare in Greece
希腊的医疗保健
Because here in Serica before in our place ah
因为之前在塞里卡，在我们这里啊
Some people really went there but didn't get proper treatment
有些人确实去了那里，但没有得到妥善治疗。
not necessarily not cured
不一定没治好。
but they must return
但他们必须返回
the entire family
全家
the entire family has already collapsed because of this, right?
整个家庭都因此而崩溃了，对吗？
Then it brings up another issue
然后，它又引出了另一个问题。
Well, uh
嗯，呃
so it talks about
所以它谈到了
Everyone's basic understanding of economics
每个人都应该对经济学有基本的了解
often overlook something called marginal cases
常常忽略所谓的边缘情况
that is to say
也就是说
It's about human needs
这关乎人类的需求
Well, generally speaking, it's flexible.
总的来说，它很灵活。
but in some aspects, it is rigid
但在某些方面，它又很僵硬。
and extremely rigid
非常刚硬
So what is the most rigid thing?
那么，最僵化的是什么？
The most rigid things are survival and reproduction
最根本的法则莫过于生存和繁衍。
right?
正确的？
This is a human need
这是人类的需求
This is rigidity
这是刚性
That is to say
也就是说
If you push the possibility of this thing toward zero
如果你把这件事发生的可能性降到零以下
At this point, the party involved is willing to pay
此时，相关方愿意支付费用。
he can pay the highest price
他可以付出最高的代价
sell off three generations of the family
卖掉三代家族财产
he is willing
他愿意
You get it, right?
你明白我的意思吧？
It's this so-called highest salary demand, right?
这就是所谓的最高薪资要求，对吧？
This is why
这就是原因
anything involving these rigid medical needs
任何涉及这些严格医疗需求的事情
This has been proven by the practice of human society
人类社会的实践已经证明了这一点。
must be regulated by the government
必须由政府监管
For example, let me give an extreme example
例如，让我举一个极端的例子。
There is no such demand in itself
本身并不存在这样的需求。
but the person who proposed it was very happy
但求婚的那个人非常高兴
booster booster, right
增压器，右边
So the state has to use
所以国家必须使用
I won't allow this thing to become a rigid demand, right?
我不会让这件事变成硬性要求，对吧？
No matter what Naxida says, ah
不管纳克西达说什么，啊
Is it everyone's own willpower that makes the choice?
每个人做出选择都是依靠自己的意志力吗？
Bullshit, right?
胡说八道，对吧？
Then then then this is is
然后，然后，这就是了。
Does this violate the fundamental principles of economics?
这是否违反了经济学的基本原理？
Actually, it's
实际上，是
And then
进而
For example, let's talk about something that might be more relatable to everyone.
例如，我们来谈谈一些大家更容易产生共鸣的话题。
Why monogamy, right?
为什么是一夫一妻制呢？
because of monogamy
因为一夫一妻制
This is also a rigid human need for reproduction
这也是人类繁衍后代的根本需求。
is a fundamental human need
这是人类的基本需求
You're not even giving him this little bit of hope
你连这点希望都不给他。
History has proven that this will lead to trouble.
历史已经证明，这样做会招致麻烦。
Therefore, the vast majority of civilized societies throughout history and across the world have made this choice.
因此，纵观历史，世界各地绝大多数文明社会都做出了这样的选择。
So if neither of these can be done
所以如果这两种方法都行不通的话
So where else can we
那么我们还能去哪里呢？
squeeze every last drop of profit out of a person
榨干一个人身上最后一滴利润
Hmph, ah
哼，啊
That would definitely be education
那绝对算是教育。
Because education is essentially the reproduction of social class, right?
因为教育本质上是社会阶级的再生产，对吧？
for example, um, buying a house
例如，嗯，买房
Because buying a house is also related to reproduction, right?
因为买房也与繁衍后代有关，对吧？
However, these two matters are not entirely without solutions.
然而，这两个问题并非完全没有解决办法。
Because after all, you might indeed have a privileged child, right?
毕竟，你的孩子很可能确实过着优渥的生活，对吧？
no education required
无需学历
you can graduate from Tsinghua or Peking University
你可以从清华大学或北京大学毕业。
that that that uh what's it called house
那，那，呃，它叫什么来着，房子
That's not necessarily the case.
情况未必如此。
Actually, renting a house isn't that unlivable, right?
其实租房住并没有那么糟糕，对吧？
Then then then what's left, what's the matter
然后，然后，还剩下什么？到底出了什么问题？
is the situation where a person is pushed to their absolute limit when facing death
是指一个人在面临死亡时被推向极限的情况。
It's best not to die instantly
最好不要立刻死去。
preferably chronic
最好是慢性
It can also repeatedly extract every last drop from you, right?
它还能反复榨干你身上的每一滴水，对吧？
Think about it, so hard to figure out
想想看，这太难搞清楚了。
What could this possibly be?
这究竟是什么？
Ah, right
啊，对
Then then then whether this thing is regulated or unregulated
然后，还要考虑这件事是否受到监管。
This is completely two different things.
这是两码事。
Absolutely, it just can't be, you can't let him think things through successfully
绝对不行，绝对不能让他把事情想清楚。
At the very least, its foundation cannot be based on a market economy.
至少，它的基础不能建立在市场经济之上。
If you follow Xi Da's approach like this
如果你像这样遵循席达的方法
You even leave the basics to the market economy
你甚至把最基本的要素都交给了市场经济。
Let me tell you
让我告诉你
Why am I telling you
我为什么要告诉你这些？
Why was the CEO of United Health executed
联合健康集团首席执行官为何被处决
Everyone applauded and cheered
众人鼓掌欢呼。
Because his claim denial rate is the highest in the United States
因为他的理赔拒赔率是全美最高的。
I looked it up, it's 55% uh
我查了一下，是 55%。
It has now reached 60%.
目前已达到 60%。
It has increased, hasn't it
确实增加了，不是吗？
Holy shit
我的天啊
Because because because because they want to withdraw
因为因为他们想退出
Because more people are canceling their insurance policies.
因为越来越多的人取消了他们的保险单。
So they have to squeeze more from a limited number of people, right?
所以他们必须从有限的人身上榨取更多价值，对吧？
More people are canceling their insurance, haha
越来越多的人取消了保险，哈哈
Aren't they afraid of getting shot?
他们难道不怕被枪击吗？
I'm curious
我很好奇
So I say again
所以我再说一遍
I don't understand American politics.
我不了解美国政治。
This still requires more input from people knowledgeable about US politics.
这仍然需要更多了解美国政治的人士提供意见。
But then again
但话又说回来……
the abolition of the ACA
废除《平价医疗法案》
It must just be the fantasy of some radical conservatives.
这一定是某些极端保守派的幻想。
or even including many fans themselves unwilling to do it
甚至包括许多不愿这样做的粉丝在内
Then the boss, the owner is the one who most doesn't want to do it
然后，老板，也就是所有者，是最不愿意做这件事的人。
They have the greatest parallel willingness
他们拥有最强的平行意愿
Really? Oh, is that so?
真的吗？哦，是这样吗？
ACA is a classic case of A4
ACA 是 A4 的一个典型案例。
AC is a typical case of doing more but earning less
AC 是一个典型的付出更多却收入更少的例子。
And then the members inside are all acting wildly.
然后，里面的成员们都开始疯狂行事。
Just imagine
试想一下
ACE has illegal immigrants
ACE 有非法移民
LGBT
with DEI
具有多元化、公平和包容性
There are all sorts of demons and monsters mixed in there
里面混杂着各种各样的恶魔和怪物。
Even you capitalists don't want to deal with these people
就连你们这些资本家都不想跟这些人打交道。
You know what
你知道吗
That's enough then
那就足够了。
So, this perfect storm in the coming months
所以，未来几个月可能会出现这种完美风暴。
I I really don't know why
我真的不知道为什么
Of course
当然
I hope we're being alarmist
我希望我们是在危言耸听。
Hopefully it's just alarmist talk
希望这只是危言耸听。
But I think among these few things
但我认为，在这几件事中，最重要的是……
Based on my understanding of the previous abundance of food under Xi's leadership
根据我对习近平领导时期粮食供应充足的了解，
I think it should be fine
我觉得应该没问题。
on the basis of milk being so cheap elsewhere
鉴于其他地方的牛奶价格如此低廉。
It's not like they can't get anything to eat at all.
他们并非完全没有东西吃。
Well, electricity isn't exactly doubling in price, right?
嗯，电价总不至于翻倍吧？
But when it comes to healthcare
但就医疗保健而言，
talking about the ACA today for the middle and lower class
今天我们来谈谈《平价医疗法案》（ACA）对中低收入阶层的影响。
If it's eight or ten times higher
如果高出八倍或十倍
This has really caused quite a few incidents, hasn't it?
这确实引发了不少事件，不是吗？
I don't know what kind of things would happen
我不知道会发生什么事。
But this really makes you imagine if you were in a situation where
但这真的会让你想象，如果你身处这样的境地：
that is to say, because of this treasure gathering producing that uh
也就是说，因为这次宝藏的收集产生了那个呃
the practice of occupying certain institutions
占领某些机构的做法
I don't know, I don't know
我不知道，我不知道
Let me correct a term
让我纠正一个术语
Denial of coverage means the insurance company refuses to insure you.
拒保是指保险公司拒绝为你提供保险。
which means unable to claim money
这意味着无法领取赔偿金
Unable to receive treatment, right?
无法接受治疗，对吗？
Claim denial, claim denial!
索赔被拒，索赔被拒！
Well, I don't know about this.
嗯，我对此并不了解。
I can hardly imagine what kind of situation it is
我简直无法想象那会是什么样的情况。
As far as I know
据我所知
in this regard
在这方面
Americans have always been very submissive.
美国人一直都很顺从。
they have a specific term
他们有一个特定的术语
that is to say, it's like saying
也就是说，这就像说
If you can't even afford your own dr.bill
如果你连自己的医生账单都付不起的话。
it's a very shameful thing
这是一件非常可耻的事情。
It's something that can't even be mentioned openly.
这是连公开提及都不能说的事情。
It's like I've never even been out there, hey
感觉就像我从未去过那里一样，嘿
China's first case due to medical expenses
中国首例因医疗费用导致的病例
Who was that person who caused a big stir?
那个引起轩然大波的人是谁？
Let me think about it
让我想想。
It seems to be the late Eastern Han Dynasty, right?
看起来像是东汉晚期，对吗？
What was that person's name again?
那个人叫什么名字来着？
No, I really forgot, it's like writer's block.
不，我真的忘了，就像写作遇到瓶颈一样。
Like the S3 brothers, right?
就像 S3 兄弟那样，对吧？
Was it Zhang Jiao and those guys?
是张娇他们那帮人吗？
Yeah, they can cure diseases, right?
是的，它们可以治愈疾病，对吧？
They can actually treat ascites
他们实际上可以治疗腹水。
In the history of Europe and America, there has never been such a person.
在欧洲和美国的历史上，从来没有过这样的人。
Not even one.
一个也没有。
Not a single one to my knowledge
据我所知，一个也没有。
Not a single one, not even Zhang Jiao, ah
一个也没有，连张娇也没有，啊
I really
我真的
Sometimes I think the title of that film is
有时我觉得那部电影的片名是
increasingly simple and unadorned
越来越简单朴素
The Silence of the Lambs
沉默的羔羊
Just you putting this kind of stuff out there
你竟然把这种东西公之于众
This would be intolerable in Serica, haha
这在塞里卡是绝对无法容忍的，哈哈
There's this meme called, uh,
有个梗叫做，呃，
just raise both hands
举起双手
Can't take it anymore
我再也受不了了
Blow them up
把它们炸掉
Ah, I can't take it anymore
啊，我再也受不了了。
punch the Earth into smithereens
把地球打成碎片
So I find myself in this position of, uh, selflessly saving all humanity
所以我发现自己身处这样的境地，呃，要无私地拯救全人类。
as well as for selfish purposes
以及出于自私的目的
Still, I would suggest Alex to, uh, get to know more female classmates, right?
不过，我还是建议 Alex 多认识一些女同学，对吧？
Ah, more development, no, oh dear
啊，又有新进展了，不，哦，天哪
Don't you dare act wild
你敢胡闹试试
You're serious, right, right?
你是认真的，对吧？
They are facing financial difficulties
他们面临财务困难
They don't know much about the University of Tokyo, right?
他们对东京大学了解不多，对吧？
Now there's also visa-free entry
现在也实行免签入境了。
that advises you
给你的建议
You should also consider your future career development
你也应该考虑一下未来的职业发展。
this path to wealth
这条致富之路
right
正确的
a new path to wealth, lying down
一条通往财富的新途径，躺下
Or maybe his father is called, uh
或许他父亲的名字叫……呃
a gambling-addicted father
一个沉迷赌博的父亲
sick mother, right?
母亲生病了，对吗？
Uh, whatever, right
呃，随便吧，对吧
Perhaps they have urgent needs
或许他们有紧急需求
needs rescue
需要救援
That's right
这是正确的
You can't possibly pay out of your own pocket to save everyone, right?
你不可能自掏腰包去拯救所有人，对吧？
You, you, you could develop a business in this area, right?
你，你，你可以在这个领域发展事业，对吧？
Right?
正确的？
Thank you
谢谢
Sorry up
抱歉
act like a fool
像个傻瓜一样
Because they believe in Jesus.
因为他们信奉耶稣。
What kind of person are you
你是什​​么样的人？
You are
你是
So you're a Protestant
所以你是新教徒
At that time, I understood.
那时我明白了。
That's fine then, hmm
那没问题，嗯。
Ah yes
啊，是的
And also, speaking of this treasure trove
还有，说到这个宝库……
This is about another terrifying aspect of American insurance.
这是美国保险业另一个令人恐惧的方面。
Do you think claim denial is already terrifying enough?
你觉得被拒赔已经够可怕的了吗？
Many times, the insurance simply denies coverage.
很多时候，保险公司会直接拒绝赔付。
When does rejection usually occur?
拒绝通常发生在什么情况下？
It happens in certain professions, you know.
你知道，这种情况在某些行业会发生。
Why do they deny coverage?
他们为什么拒绝承保？
Simply put
简而言之
that is, certain technical jobs
也就是说，某些技术性工作
upon reaching a certain age or under certain circumstances
达到一定年龄或在特定情况下
they won't cover you anymore
他们不会再为你提供保险了。
Some say isn't this something the company provides insurance for?
有人说，这难道不是公司会提供保险的吗？
But what does the company base its insurance coverage on?
但该公司的保险范围是基于什么呢？
For example, electricians
例如，电工
climbing utility poles
爬电线杆
Everyone has seen it, right?
大家都看过了吧？
electricians
电工
He needs an electrician's license.
他需要一张电工执照。
Those power companies base their decisions on the electrician's certification.
这些电力公司会根据电工的资格证书来做决定。
with this certificate in hand can you go to the insurance company
凭这份证明，你可以去保险公司。
purchase his industry-specific insurance
购买他所在行业的保险
one license
一张许可证
an insurance policy
保险单
No license, no insurance
无驾照，无保险
Some people say isn't this quite good
有人说，这难道不是相当不错吗？
Well, here comes the problem.
问题就在这里。
The insurance for professionals is many times that of ordinary individuals.
专业人士的保险费用是普通人的数倍。
Some people say
有人说
So how much can one actually receive?
那么一个人实际能收到多少钱呢？
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
If an ordinary person's accident insurance costs $100 per month
如果普通人的意外保险每月费用为 100 美元。
if you're an electrician
如果你是一名电工
The cost can even reach $500
费用甚至可能高达 500 美元。
600 dollars
600 美元
$700
700 美元
Do you understand my concept?
你理解我的意思吗？
Do you understand this concept?
你理解这个概念吗？
That is, if you are an electrician
也就是说，如果你是一名电工
Primary, intermediate, advanced, or specialized, no matter what?
无论是初级、中级、高级还是专业，都一样？
your premiums are skyrocketing
你的保费飙升了
exponentially increasing
指数级增长
perhaps an ordinary young person your age
或许你只是一个和你同龄的普通年轻人。
his premium would be eighty to one hundred
他的保费大概是八十到一百。
you might have to pay five or six hundred, even seven or eight hundred
你可能要付五六百，甚至七八百。
This amount of money, right?
就是这个数额的钱，对吧？
Basically, it's all covered by the company.
基本上，所有费用都由公司承担。
If you are a full-time employee
如果您是全职员工
Some people say then part-time workers don't need to buy it, right?
有人说，兼职员工就不需要购买了，对吗？
Part-time workers don't need to buy it
兼职员工无需购买。
but there will be penalties
但会有处罚。
because if there's an issue with this kind of specialized technical operation
因为如果这种专业技术操作出现问题……
found that insurance was not purchased
发现并未购买保险。
will be fined severely
将受到严厉罚款
So he actually doesn't dare to mess around too much
所以他其实不敢太过放肆。
However, there is racial discrimination involved.
然而，其中涉及种族歧视。
What is racial discrimination?
什么是种族歧视？
The electrician license in the U.S. is for electricians
美国的电工执照是颁发给电工的。
A Mexican electrician's license is also an electrician's license.
墨西哥的电工执照也是电工执照。
The North American economic and trade integration has brought about many aspects
北美经济和贸易一体化带来了诸多方面的影响。
including academic credential recognition
包括学历证书认可
including certification authentication
包括证书认证
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
Why should I hire an American electrician?
我为什么要聘请美国电工？
Are Mexican electricians not good enough? Ah
墨西哥的电工技术不够好吗？啊
Hey, old A, I wanted to ask about the work-related injury insurance at Western University
嘿，老 A，我想问问西安大略大学的工伤保险。
Can work-related injury insurance usually be claimed, ah?
通常情况下，工伤保险可以理赔吗？
Work injury insurance is almost the most difficult to claim.
工伤保险几乎是最难索赔的。
that is, you almost as if
也就是说，你几乎就像
even if you have surveillance footage
即使你有监控录像
it's also difficult to prove whether it was due to your own operational error
而且也很难证明这是否是由于你自身的操作失误造成的。
resulting in an accidental incident
导致意外事故
Oh no no no no, not to the commerce bureau
哦不不不不，千万别去商务局
You say yes to all these first
你首先对所有这些都说“是”。
Because here in our place
因为在这里，在我们这里
In our line of work, as long as you can say it happened
在我们这行，只要你能说这件事发生过就行。
is the problem that occurred during work
这是工作中出现的问题。
most can be reimbursed
大部分费用都可以报销。
It's not like the vast majority can absolutely get reimbursed.
绝大多数人并非都能获得全额赔偿。
Absolutely not
绝对不是
Well, anyway, as for industrial and commercial insurance, I know how it works in China.
总之，至于工商业保险，我知道它在中国是如何运作的。
but in China, accident insurance
但在中国，意外保险
It's the relationship between the insurance company and the individual, right?
这是保险公司和个人之间的关系，对吧？
because of industry and commerce
因为工商业
especially when it involves special categories of occupations such as Class 3 or Class 4 jobs
尤其当涉及特殊类别的职业，例如三级或四级工作时更是如此。
like electricians
比如电工
things like working at heights
比如高空作业
the claims for these things require
这些要求需要
First, it needs to be assessed by the local human resources and social security department
首先，需要由当地人力资源和社会保障部门进行评估。
then it will be covered
然后它就会被覆盖。
That is to say, the first step is to report the case to the human resources and social security department, um, ah.
也就是说，第一步是向人力资源和社会保障部门报告此案，嗯，啊。
so uh further compensation
所以，呃，进一步的补偿
it is definitely there
它肯定在那里。
This is not something the insurance company can decide, okay?
这并非保险公司可以决定的事情，明白吗？
It is intervened by the higher-level authorities.
此事由上级部门介入。
Um, uh, sir
嗯，呃，先生
I would like to ask
我想问
Does this Workers' Compensation Insurance from Xida have
西达提供的这份工伤赔偿保险有吗？
that is to say, there is a time limit
也就是说，是有时间限制的。
That is to say, how long after the injury can you report it to be considered valid?
也就是说，受伤后多久才能报案才算有效？
There is usually a time limit for that
通常会有时间限制。
Each industry is different
每个行业的情况都不尽相同。
But there is a time limit for it.
但这样做是有时间限制的。
Let me finish speaking
让我说完。
Someone said that, uh, uh, uh, uh, that certification is from me, let me read the SC
有人说，呃，呃，呃，呃，那份证明是我出的，让我看看 SC（最高法院）的记录。
Thanks to Brother Zhen for the generous reward
感谢甄哥的慷慨赏赐
Add more damn pictures
多加点该死的图片
It feels like we've covered tonight's topic pretty thoroughly.
感觉我们今晚的话题已经讨论得相当透彻了。
Yesterday I came across something
昨天我偶然发现了一些东西
This cover really gave me a huge shock.
这个封面真的让我大吃一惊。
What Old A called the 'American fake smile' is probably this kind, huh?
老 A 所说的“美国式假笑”大概就是这种吧？
Let me show you guys, alright
让我给你们演示一下，好吗？
It's even more terrifying compared to this
比这更可怕
He lacks sunshine
他缺乏阳光
It's just not that kind of California-style rare three-fan illusion
这并非加州那种罕见的三扇扇幻觉
This fake smile is pretty average.
这种假笑很普通。
It doesn't look that creepy.
看起来没那么吓人。
There are much more terrifying fake smiles than this, right?
还有比这更可怕的假笑呢，对吧？
Let me show you, okay
让我来给你演示一下，好吗？
How fake can his illusions be
他的幻觉究竟有多么虚假？
In the U.S., insurance doesn't pay out like this.
在美国，保险赔付并非如此。
Sigh, some people say the probability of such claim denials is high
唉，有人说这种索赔被拒的概率很高。
Then do you still have to buy it?
那你还一定要买吗？
Mandatory purchase
强制购买
not allowed to join the union
不允许加入工会
They are in cahoots with the unions.
他们与工会勾结。
Someone said, 'Can I buy a cheaper one?' No, you can't.
有人问：“我可以买个便宜点的吗？” 不，你不能。
Because the union has already set the rules
因为工会已经制定了规则。
what kind of insurance you can buy from which company
你可以从哪家公司购买哪种保险
You have no freedom of choice
你没有选择的自由。
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
that is, you cannot choose
也就是说，你不能选择
What insurance did you buy
你买了什么保险？
you're in this industry
你身处这个行业
the union in this industry
该行业的工会
has already completed a purchasing agreement with a certain health insurance company
已与某健康保险公司签订采购协议
they had already made a deal
他们已经达成协议了。
sold you out
出卖了你
You simply have no choice
你别无选择
Got it
知道了
you simply can't choose
你根本无法选择
You want to freely choose an insurance plan
你想自由选择保险计划
Sorry
对不起
The union doesn't recognize it
工会不承认它
Yes, that's his freedom
是的，那是他的自由
You need to consider those local Putian-style hospitals
你需要考虑一下莆田式的本地医院。
Which insurance companies are good, right?
哪些保险公司比较好？
Don't say that you're covered for something on the East Coast
别说你在东海岸有保险。
you're on the West Coast
你现在在西海岸
Well, uh, oh my, this is extremely fragmented
呃，我的天，这太零散了。
Everyone has their own means of making a living.
每个人都有自己的谋生手段。
And everyone must not forget
每个人都不能忘记
Everything we're discussing today is just the damn healthcare line.
我们今天讨论的一切都只是该死的医保线。
You should know that in the East
你应该知道，在东方
Medical insurance is the cheapest among all types of insurance.
在所有保险类型中，医疗保险是最便宜的。
critical illness insurance
重大疾病保险
life insurance
人寿保险
annuity insurance
年金保险
dividend insurance
分红保险
We haven't even mentioned a single word yet
我们甚至连一个字都没提过。
Well, the problem for the American people is
嗯，美国人民面临的问题是……
just for health insurance alone
仅仅为了医疗保险
he can already barely afford it
他本来就几乎负担不起。
So for us Easterners, the middle class is struggling with
所以对我们东方人来说，中产阶级正面临着……
should buy or not
买还是不买
which one is cost-effective or not
哪种更划算？
This is not a luxury they can afford
这是他们负担不起的奢侈品。
can afford the luxury to consider
有能力承担考虑这种奢侈的后果
The problem is that's something only decent people can talk about, right?
问题是，只有正派的人才能谈论这种话题，对吧？
It's something only decent people can talk about.
只有正派的人才能谈论这种话题。
Hey boss, I have another question
老板，我还有个问题
I used to read that before
我以前读过那篇文章。
also read those Yi Lin
也读了那些易林的文章
I also saw that before
我之前也看到过。
Those books say things like uh
那些书里会说一些类似“呃……”之类的话。
The Greeks are particularly good at donating money.
希腊人特别擅长捐款。
What is this issue
这是什么问题？
Is this still happening now?
现在这种情况还在发生吗？
that is to say, they donated to show me
也就是说，他们捐款是为了让我看到
What are they saying? Oh right, the injured ones.
他们在说什么？哦，对了，是受伤的人。
that is, the so-called donation to the injured
也就是说，就是所谓的向伤者捐款
it's just that, how should I put it
就是这样，该怎么说呢？
This is a form of mutual assistance within the community.
这是社区内的一种互助形式。
In essence, it is the entire society
从本质上讲，它就是整个社会
a manifestation of the complete failure of the government
这是政府彻底失败的体现。
self-regulation
自我调节
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
Uh-huh, got it
嗯，明白了。
Well, well, no one can help anymore
唉，唉，已经没人能帮上忙了。
Simply put, the government is ineffective.
简而言之，政府效率低下。
Companies show no humanity
企业毫无人性可言。
The insurance companies are predatory
保险公司是掠夺性的。
Let's help each other out
让我们互相帮助吧
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
This is clearly a manifestation of government dysfunction.
这显然是政府失职的表现。
They shamelessly hype it up as some kind of mutual aid among people
他们厚颜无耻地将其吹捧为人们之间的一种互助行为。
There is true love among people
人与人之间存在着真爱。
I'm so awesome
我太棒了
think these people are awesome
我觉得这些人太棒了
You know what
你知道吗
boasting about this kind of thing
吹嘘这种事
Because what did they eat back then?
他们那时候都吃什么呢？
Look at how Greece does it, you see, once someone gets injured,
你看看希腊是怎么做的，一旦有人受伤，
so everyone helps each other, right
所以大家都会互相帮助，对吧？
Look at how others are doing
看看其他人是怎么做的。
I have also participated in such mutual aid meetings
我也曾参加过类似的互助会议。
I went to help a redneck brother
我去帮一个乡巴佬兄弟。
His son was also in this situation
他的儿子也面临同样的情况。
You know
你知道
Everyone gathers together
大家聚集在一起
People in a community participate in mutual aid meetings
社区居民参加互助会议
Whose child has encountered what kind of misfortune
谁的孩子遭遇了什么样的不幸
what kind of disaster has befallen them
他们遭遇了什么样的灾难？
How is the situation now
现在情况如何？
How much money is needed
需要多少钱
what supplies are needed
需要哪些物资
Everyone pitching in already brings us very close to the state of primitive humans.
大家齐心协力已经使我们非常接近原始人类的状态。
You know what
你知道吗
That's not about food, right
那跟食物无关，对吧？
It's when someone has that, no, not an undercover agent
就是当有人拥有那种能力的时候，不，不是卧底特工。
Everyone come out and lend a hand
大家都出来帮忙吧！
No more, wow, okay
好了，没事了。
It's just that primitive.
它就是这么原始。
Thanks to Haoyue's Dream
感谢昊岳之梦
Red Brother's big reward
红兄弟的大奖励
Chinese-style sweet girl
中国风甜美女孩
American-style modern production girls
美式现代制作女孩
Oh wow, this is just too classic, isn't it?
哇，这简直太经典了，不是吗？
Come on
快点
Some say sunshine fake yang yang
有人说阳光是假阳阳
sunny and cheerful
阳光明媚，心情愉快
What does a fake smile girl look like
一个笑容虚假的女孩长什么样？
Let me show you a more classic example of the 'Dream of the Bright Moon'.
让我给你展示一个更经典的“明月之梦”的例子。
This picture from the Hongbao Pavilion is fucking
这张红包阁的照片真是太他妈棒了
I'm not
我不是
China's Five-Year Economic Plan The China Show
中国五年经济计划 中国展
Take a look
看看
Ah
啊
planning
规划
Oh, sometimes even sages and great men
哦，有时就连圣贤和伟人也会如此。
Yes
是的
Well, is this kind of mutual aid association effective sometimes?
那么，这种互助组织有时真的有效吗？
not very good
不太好
If it weren't for my penicillin
如果不是因为我用了青霉素
And if it weren't for my antibiotics, right
如果不是因为抗生素，对吧？
redneck buddy
乡巴佬哥们
his son wouldn't have survived either
他的儿子也活不下来。
I provided a lot of meat, right?
我提供了很多肉，对吧？
Those are all secondary.
这些都是次要的。
The most important thing is penicillin, right?
最重要的是青霉素，对吧？
Taking antibiotics made me feel much better.
服用抗生素后我感觉好多了。
This doesn't even look human anymore.
这看起来完全不像人类了。
Then you think it just doesn't look human, alright
那你就会觉得它看起来不像人类，好吧。
Someone said this is talking so much about the boss, hmm
有人说这话里有很多关于老板的意味，嗯。
20 I noticed they really like tanning.
20 我注意到他们真的很喜欢晒日光浴。
Because for white people, it's about being wealthy
因为对白人来说，一切都关乎财富。
A sign of being a middle-class white person is getting a tan.
晒黑是中产阶级白人的标志之一。
If you don't get a tan, it makes you look poor.
如果你没晒黑，会显得你很穷。
Thanks to Cool Old Goose for the reward
感谢 Cool Old Goose 的奖励
Their system
他们的系统
Why does it feel like the situation in Region A is much more severe than in our country?
为什么感觉 A 区的情况比我们国家严重得多？
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
I'm from Henan. In the early years, people from other places often called me a manhole cover thief.
我来自河南。早年间，外地人常叫我“井盖小偷”。
But in recent years, I feel they just tease like this
但近年来，我觉得他们只是这样戏弄人。
even when introducing themselves
即使在自我介绍时也是如此
they would also say I'm from the place where manhole covers are stolen
他们还会说我来自一个井盖经常被偷的地方。
Because regional discrimination in China is relatively mild.
因为中国的地域歧视现象相对较轻。
Your American regional discrimination is the most terrifying.
你们美国人对美国地域的歧视是最可怕的。
Someone asked how terrifying it could be
有人问这到底有多可怕。
American consortiums are all named after regions
美国所有财团都以地区命名。
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
even if some consortiums don't have the name on them
即使有些财团没有署名
but essentially they are also initiated based on regions
但本质上，它们也是根据地区而发起的。
They are everywhere, just like those 'transportation brigade leaders', you know?
他们无处不在，就像那些“运输队队长”一样，你知道吗？
Ah, right, right
啊，对，对
Let me say it again
让我再说一遍
Right, speaking of hell
对了，说到地狱
You should know that
你应该知道这一点
For example, if you work in different professions across different states
例如，如果你在不同州从事不同的职业。
For example, if you work as an electrician in Washington State
例如，如果你在华盛顿州从事电工工作。
to California
到加利福尼亚
your insurance has to be changed
你的保险需要更改。
because the local unions in California and the insurance companies in California
因为加州的当地工会和加州的保险公司
colluded
串通
you change jobs
你换工作了
you have to change your insurance
你必须更换你的保险
If you can
如果可以的话
If you can still stay within the coverage area of your original insurance company
如果你还能继续留在原保险公司的承保范围内的话
within the coverage area
在覆盖范围内
You don't need to once you're out of their coverage area
一旦你离开他们的服务范围，就不需要了。
You'd better switch to another one.
你最好换一个。
I would like to ask, in this particular situation
我想问，在这种特殊情况下
If it's just an internal company transfer to another region
如果只是公司内部调动到其他地区
Is this also necessary
这也有必要吗？
Yeah, ah, yes, yes, there is
是的，啊，是的，是的，有
And let me tell you all
让我来告诉你们这一切
Why would anyone still buy it?
为什么还会有人买它？
It's forcibly bundled
它是被强制捆绑的
You know what
你知道吗
your company in this state
贵公司在该州
In reality, most of the time you have no choice.
事实上，大多数时候你别无选择。
you don't provide this for your employees
你没有为你的员工提供这项服务。
he has no other choice
他别无选择
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
it's like you're right
你说的没错。
It seems like you have choices
看来你有很多选择。
In fact, you don't have different industries
事实上，你们并没有不同的行业。
has already been carved up by different insurance companies
已被不同的保险公司瓜分。
Do you understand what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
You actually have no choice but to buy
你实际上别无选择，只能购买。
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
It's possible that you may be within this company's
你有可能就在这家公司里
you may have issues with a specific business of this company
您可能与该公司的某个特定业务存在问题。
some certain insurance
某些保险
Differences may exist regarding specific items
具体项目可能存在差异
But only this company understands it, right?
但只有这家公司明白这一点，对吧？
This is United Healthcare
这是联合健康保险公司
The rejection rate is almost fucking 60%
拒绝率几乎高达 60%。
Why are people still buying it
为什么还有人买它？
You can't escape it. In certain states and industries, that's the only option available.
你无法逃避。在某些州和某些行业，这是唯一的选择。
unless you move
除非你搬家
unless you change jobs
除非你换工作
otherwise you can't escape
否则你就无法逃脱
Do you understand what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
If you are among those 160 million people with formal jobs
如果你是那 1.6 亿拥有正式工作的人之一
Your health insurance plan is no longer your decision.
你的健康保险计划不再由你决定。
Your employer has already decided
你的雇主已经决定了
The entire company is on this plan
整个公司都在执行这项计划。
You want to add coverage
您想增加保险范围
you have to pay extra
你需要额外付费。
If the company's boss or HR decides to use United Healthcare
如果公司老板或人力资源部门决定使用联合健康保险
you can only use United Healthcare
您只能使用联合健康保险
you can get insured
你可以投保
you already belong to that top 160 million people
你已经属于那前 1.6 亿人之中了。
Yes, your so-called choice is to choose ACC
是的，你所谓的选择就是选择 ACC。
you can't get in line
你没法排队
not in the top 1.61
未进入前 1.61 名
only then can you resort to turning to the ACA
只有到那时，你才能求助于《平价医疗法案》（ACA）。
It seems like there are some choices
似乎有一些选择。
Well, essentially there's no real choice.
其实，基本上没有真正的选择。
Actually, these are all just the same few big corporations.
实际上，这些都是同一批大型企业。
Some say this is so not capitalist, right?
有人说这完全不符合资本主义精神，对吧？
This is the ultimate form of capitalism
这是资本主义的终极形式。
monopoly capital
垄断资本
Trust monopoly
信托垄断
Some might say, can't you just buy cheaper options?
有人可能会问，难道不能买更便宜的替代品吗？
but it's just a matter of whether this company's prices are expensive or cheap
但问题就在于这家公司的价格是贵还是便宜。
You still can't escape the grasp of his palm, the Five Finger Mountain.
你仍然无法逃脱他那只手掌——五指山——的掌控。
It's merely a difference of which finger you're being pressed under.
区别仅仅在于按压你的是哪根手指而已。
It's convenient to play a video at this moment.
现在播放视频很方便。
saw a few days ago
几天前看到的
Always feel like remembering something
总感觉应该想起什么事。
It took me all night to find it again
我花了一整夜才再次找到它。
The level of hell is quite high
地狱的等级相当高。
See if it can be played
看看能不能玩。
Ah, the cold father has turned into warm numbers.
啊，冷酷的父亲变成了温暖的数字。
This is quite common, you know
这种情况很常见，你知道的。
Come on, let's take a look
来吧，我们一起来看看。
The cold father has turned into warm numbers
冷漠的父亲变成了温暖的数字
Congratulations
恭喜！
He is the one millionth deceased since the hospital's opening.
他是这家医院开业以来第一百万名逝者。
One million death
一百万人死亡
How do the previous two generations feel, may I ask?
请问前两代人有何感想？
What is wrong with you people
你们这些人到底怎么了？
I was devastated, he was my father
我悲痛欲绝，他是我父亲。
This is a difficult time for our family
这对我们家来说是一个艰难的时期。
Why would we want to celebrate this
我们为什么要庆祝这件事？
His final act in life was a monumental achievement
他生前的最后举动是一项意义非凡的成就。
Congratulations
恭喜！
You are a one million customer
您是百万级客户
This year
今年
We are mourning the loss of my father.
我们正在哀悼我父亲的去世。
Can't this wait a hundred and seventy five thousand
难道不能等十七万五千美元吗？
We can't afford that
我们负担不起。
We we gave you a discount on the aspirin
我们给了你阿司匹林的折扣。
So forty dollars
所以四十美元
A pillars of discount sry that that should be sixty
折扣支柱，抱歉，应该是六十
It's half off
半价
Congratulations
恭喜！
You're the one million parking violations
你是那第一百万张违章停车罚单。
You toed our car
你撞了我们的车
Our kids were in there
我们的孩子当时也在里面。
What you left the kids in the car
你把孩子留在车里了
Then tell me what to do? Let him witness his grandfather's death with his own eyes?
那你告诉我该怎么办？让他亲眼目睹祖父的死亡吗？
Let them see grandpa die death
让他们亲眼目睹爷爷的死亡
Uh human is a natural part of life
人类是生命自然的一部分
As for abandonment and letting a child be kidnapped, that's certainly not.
至于遗弃和放任儿童被绑架，那肯定不是。
And abducted is not
而绑架并非如此。
Okay
好的
Sir
先生
Oh! Doctor, we didn't abandon our child, he was taken away by a tow truck!
哦！医生，我们没有遗弃孩子，他是被拖车拉走了！
Our children
我们的孩子
They were toed away in a car
他们被车开走了
Congratulations
恭喜！
Hh
嗯
You two are the one millionth pair to neglect your parents
你们俩是第一百万个不孝顺父母的孩子了。
Megalyour
巨型
Parents
父母
Ha ha ha ha ha ha where are our children
哈哈哈哈哈哈，我们的孩子在哪里？
They're going in foster care
他们将被送去寄养家庭。
Please no I just want my kids back
求求你们不要，我只想我的孩子回来。
No
不
I just want my honey to come back, congratulations
我只希望我的爱人回来，恭喜你。
Ah you just won ten million dollars from your father's life
啊，你刚刚从你父亲的遗产中赢得了 1000 万美元。
Insurance policy
保单
This is absolutely an American hell joke.
这绝对是个美国式的地狱笑话。
Oh my god
我的天啊
The concentration is a bit too low or too high
浓度有点低或有点高
Sigh
叹
Ah, thank you Brother Digongzhiquan for the tip.
啊，谢谢地宫之泉兄弟的指点。
Let me take a look
让我看看
I used to work in the insurance industry.
我以前在保险行业工作。
and other insurance
以及其他保险
collaboration with Europe and America
与欧洲和美国合作
I feel like domestic insurance and foreign insurance, uh, wait a second
我觉得国内保险和国外保险，呃，等等
are entirely two different concepts under the same term
这是同一个术语下的两个完全不同的概念。
So I haven't heard the whole story about this matter today
所以今天我还没有听到关于这件事的全部经过。
but want to share some insights
但我想分享一些见解
Just as an additional perspective
仅作为一种补充视角
To be fair
公平地说
During my years working in the field
在我从事该领域工作的这些年里
The gemstones from XiDa almost completely outshine domestic ones in every aspect
西大宝石在各个方面几乎都完胜国产宝石。
Their solutions and technologies do have remarkable advantages
他们的解决方案和技术确实具有显著优势。
but the path is wrong
但这条路错了。
is never an empty phrase
这绝非一句空话。
In recent years, the trend of the West declining while the East rises has become increasingly evident.
近年来，西方衰落而东方崛起的趋势越来越明显。
To elaborate
详细说明
First, domestic gemstones are looked down upon by the financial industry
首先，国产宝石受到金融行业的轻视。
There is a reason why it's at the bottom of the chain
它之所以位于产业链的最底端，是有原因的。
money bag
钱袋
even acting as a black-and-white glove
甚至可以充当黑白手套
Overall, it serves as a tool and leverage for governance.
总的来说，它可作为治理的工具和杠杆。
the four major domestic treasures
国内四大瑰宝
three are wholly state-owned central enterprises
三家均为国有中央企业
must resolutely obey the leadership
必须坚决服从领导
even if it is purely privately owned
即使它是完全私有的
must also obey orders
还必须服从命令
Keep social responsibility in mind
牢记社会责任。
the most basic hope lies with the salt merchants
最基本的希望寄托在盐商身上。
The salt merchants refuse to pay when they really should not pay
盐商们明明不应该付钱，却拒绝付款。
Even if it should be covered, they still won't pay
即使本应由保险公司承担，他们仍然不会支付。
have no choice
别无选择
would rather settle out of court
宁愿庭外和解。
The Dongda Insurance Company has to pay even if they say they won't.
即使东大保险公司声称不会赔付，他们也必须赔付。
The insurance regulatory court compels payment despite claim rejection
即使索赔被拒，保险监管法院仍强制支付。
Similarly, it doesn't matter if you involve relevant leaders from the insurance regulatory or private insurance sectors.
同样，邀请保险监管机构或私人保险部门的相关领导人参与也无关紧要。
Having a court judgment is enough to settle the matter
有了法院判决就足以解决问题。
But foreign insurance companies are effectively part of the ruling class
但外国保险公司实际上是统治阶级的一部分。
itself
本身
Specifically
具体来说
capitalist lawyers
资本主义律师
guild doctors
行会医生
guild actuaries
行会精算师
Accounting Guild
会计协会
wealthy individuals with tax avoidance needs
有避税需求的富裕人士
a platform for weaving networks, colluding, and sharing interests
一个用于构建网络、串通和分享利益的平台
This is why bail deduction authority in the U.S. is even higher than that of banks
这就是为什么美国的保释金扣除权限甚至比银行的权限还要高。
the reason, okay
原因，好的
And there's also the aspect of premium investment, reinsurance, and double insurance design.
此外，还有保费投资、再保险和双重保险设计等方面的问题。
Why do insurance companies have higher deduction authority than banks?
为什么保险公司的扣款权限比银行高？
You big gemstones play way too many tricks in the investment market
你们这些大宝石在投资市场玩弄了太多花招。
too aggressive
过于激进
Although there are explicit restrictions on the proportion of insurance funds entering the market
尽管对进入市场的保险基金比例有明确的限制
but various credit guarantees, asset packages, and equity products
但包括各种信用担保、资产组合和股权产品。
The result is high risk and high return
结果就是高风险高回报。
too big to fail when things go wrong
规模太大，出问题时不会倒闭
renowned
著名
subprime mortgage crisis
次贷危机
the renowned American International Insurance Group
著名的美国国际保险集团
was also a key behind-the-scenes player
他也是一位重要的幕后人物。
credit insurance
信用保险
The result was that the federal government had to massively bail out with public funds.
结果是联邦政府不得不动用公共资金进行大规模救助。
while Lehman Brothers went straight into bankruptcy
而雷曼兄弟则直接破产了。
a Naya-led diagram of major healthcare reforms under the Schina administration
纳亚主导绘制的席娜政府时期重大医疗改革示意图
The sudden association feels somewhat similar to the fallen hostels of the Soviet Union.
这种突如其来的联想，让人感觉有点像苏联时期那些倒塌的青年旅舍。
nominally serving the entire population
名义上服务于全体人口
In practice, it can only take from those who have little
实际上，它只能从那些贫穷的人身上掠夺。
to give to those who already have more than enough
给予那些已经拥有足够多资源的人
To put it bluntly, it's about treating people differently based on their status.
说得直白些，这就是根据人们的地位区别对待他们。
robbing Peter to pay Paul with resources meant to serve ordinary people
拆东墙补西墙，用原本服务于普通民众的资源来支付保罗的薪水。
to the upper class
对上层阶级而言
That's how it is
就是这样。
Sigh, someone said that's industry insurance
唉，有人说那是行业保险。
Well, what else is there in industry insurance?
那么，工业保险领域还有哪些其他方面呢？
Home insurance is the most terrifying thing
房屋保险是最可怕的事情
Some people say
有人说
Is property tax the scariest aspect of owning a home in the US?
在美国，房产税是拥有房产最令人担忧的方面吗？
No
不
it's the homeowner's insurance
这是房主保险
Property tax typically charges around 2%.
房产税通常约为 2%。
on average, a house
平均而言，一栋房子
For example, your house is worth 1 million
例如，你的房子价值 100 万美元。
You pay $20,000 in property taxes per year.
你每年缴纳 2 万美元的房产税。
There are also property fees
此外还有房产费
property fees and that home insurance
房产费和房屋保险
Oh
哦
Both of them are also charged based on the property value
两者的费用均按房产价值计算。
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
For example, if you bought a house at the age of 20
例如，如果你在 20 岁时买了一套房子
worth 1 million
价值 100 万美元
This house is now worth 5 million when you're 70 years old.
当你 70 岁时，这栋房子价值 500 万美元。
it has increased fivefold in 50 years
50 年来，它增长了五倍。
Then don't be happy
那就别高兴。
Insurance premiums will increase
保险费将会上涨
property fees and taxes will increase
房产费用和税费将会增加
Property taxes will also rise
房产税也将上涨
And they are all proportional, you get it?
它们都是成比例的，你明白吗？
The high cost is proportional damage, you get it?
高昂的代价与造成的损失成正比，你明白吗？
Do you understand his Vayne passive three-ring effect?
你了解薇恩被动技能的三环效果吗？
It deducts a percentage of the max health.
它会扣除最大生命值的一定比例。
Some people mention insurance
有些人提到了保险。
How expensive can the insurance be?
保险费用能有多高？
Well, it depends on how decent your house is, okay?
那得看你的房子条件怎么样了，好吗？
The more upscale the house, the more expensive it is.
房子越高档，价格就越贵。
Some people say
有人说
Generally speaking, it's roughly a bit cheaper than property taxes, but not by much.
总的来说，它比房产税略便宜一些，但差别不大。
So don't assume that property taxes are the end of it.
所以不要以为房产税就万事大吉了。
No, that's not the case
不，并非如此。
home insurance property tax
房屋保险房产税
property fees must also be paid
还必须支付物业费。
Some say the proportion paid is uh
有人说支付的比例是呃
approximately one-third to one-half of the property tax
大约占房产税的三分之一到二分之一
if the property tax is 2% of the total home price
如果房产税为房屋总价的 2%
then the home insurance is basically 0.66%
那么房屋保险基本上就是 0.66%。
around 1%
约 1%
if it's not a luxury home
如果不是豪华住宅的话
just an ordinary house
只是一栋普通的房子
Ah, and there's also the property management fee.
啊，还有物业管理费呢。
Some say can property management fees even be considered?
有人说，物业管理费是否可以考虑？
Right
正确的
The property management fee is 0.2% of the total house price
物业管理费为房屋总价的 0.2%。
ranging from 0.5%
范围从 0.5%起
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
You own a house
你拥有一套房子
This house is worth 1 million dollars.
这栋房子价值一百万美元。
Your annual mandatory expenses amount to 20 dollars.
您的年度强制性支出为 20 美元。
Your annual mandatory expenses are approximately $340,000.
您的年度强制性支出约为 340,000 美元。
which is 3% of the total house price
相当于房屋总价的 3%。
nearly 4%
近 4%
Sometimes what does home insurance even cover? Like if it burns down
有时候，房屋保险到底能赔付哪些费用？比如房屋被烧毁的情况。
rebuild a Li wedding dress for you
为您重新设计一件李氏婚纱
Thank you
谢谢
Country, hmm, OK, oh
乡村，嗯，好的，哦
If the price of a house in the U.S. drops
如果美国房价下跌
the previously increased property fees and property taxes
此前增加的物业费和物业税
Do you still have to pay based on the highest historical property price?
是否仍需按照历史最高房价支付？
No, the tax reduction will not be granted.
不，减税申请将不予批准。
First, the house price has dropped
首先，房价下跌了。
If the drop in housing prices is due to your actions
如果房价下跌是由于你的行为造成的
you'll just have to wait for liquidation
你只能等清算了。
Someone said
有人说
Why is it that I'm speaking now
我为什么现在要说话呢？
Why do all social classes in the United States
为什么美国所有社会阶层
For example, the middle class needs to maintain their dignity
例如，中产阶级需要维护他们的尊严。
You have to maintain, you have to maintain housing prices
你必须维持，你必须维持房价
This is different from the Chinese logic
这与中国的逻辑不同。
As long as it's a major city, housing prices will rise everywhere.
只要是主要城市，房价就会上涨。
rising everywhere
到处都在上升
This is not the American way
这不是美国的方式
The U.S. is specifically divided into communities.
美国明显划分为不同的社区。
The housing prices in your community are collectively maintained by all the residents living there
您所在社区的房价是由所有居民共同维持的。
collectively maintained
集体维护
What it means in the US is
在美国，它的意思是：
a building is worth only one dollar
一栋建筑物只值一美元。
and a building worth $10 million
还有一栋价值 1000 万美元的建筑
may be adjacent
可能相邻
two communities
两个社区
separated by just one street
仅隔一条街道
Got it?
知道了？
two communities on either side of the street
街道两旁是两个社区
Here, a house can be sold for just one dollar
在这里，一套房子只需一美元就能卖掉。
a house over there sells for 10 million
那边的一栋房子卖 1000 万美元。
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
It doesn't consider the overall development of the city.
它没有考虑到城市的整体发展。
how the people in your community maintain the community
你所在社区的人们如何维护社区
determines the housing prices in this community
决定该社区房价的因素
Then tell me
然后告诉我
Can you afford not to maintain appearances?
你能承担不维护体面的后果吗？
Do you dare not maintain this decency
你竟敢违背这份体面？
The homeowners association can force you into compulsory liquidation
业主协会可以强制你进行清算。
forcing you to sell your house
迫使你卖掉房子
Why don't they lower housing prices sometimes
为什么他们有时不降低房价呢？
pay less taxes
少缴税
Telling me this is pretty much useless, right?
告诉我这些基本没用，对吧？
Go tell that to the rich people
你去跟有钱人说说这话。
Oh, you're talking about that 1% property insurance, huh?
哦，你说的是那 1%的财产保险啊？
Like those in California,
就像加州的那些人一样，
Last time there was a big fire, weren't there many wealthy people
上次发生大火的时候，是不是有很多富人？
they choose to be in that kind of
他们选择处于那种状态
Well, I don't know
嗯，我不知道。
in their case
就他们而言
Do they have a community?
他们有自己的社区吗？
that is, the kind of standalone luxury homes in the forest
也就是说，森林里那种独立的豪华住宅。
It's considered to have a community
它被认为拥有一个社区
or is there no community
或者根本没有社区
I'm quite curious about this.
我对此很好奇。
a standalone mansion in the forest
森林中的一座独立豪宅
That's what you see in the photos
这就是你在照片里看到的。
You think you're in a standalone mansion in the forest
你以为自己身处森林中一座独立的豪宅里
You look at the satellite map
你查看卫星地图
you will know
你会知道
It must definitely be in a community.
它肯定位于某个社区内。
most likely
最有可能的
not in the same community
不属于同一个社区
Who built the road right up to your house?
谁修了这条直通你家门口的路？
Where does your sewer discharge to?
你们的污水排放到哪里？
Who's your daddy for water, electricity, heating, and ventilation?
谁负责你的水、电、暖气和通风？
It's nothing more than a higher density compared to the others.
它只不过是比其他材料密度更高而已。
It simply has a lower density with each household occupying a larger area
它的密度较低，每户家庭占用的面积更大。
but not without neighborhoods
但并非没有社区
the kind that literally occupies an entire hill
那种占据整座山丘的山丘
that kind of self-developed property without neighbors
那种没有邻居的自建房产
That's not something ordinary wealthy people can afford.
那是普通富人负担不起的。
That requires someone extremely wealthy.
那需要极其富有的人。
and there was also a historical opportunity
此外，还有一个历史性的机遇。
back in the pioneering days, right
回到拓荒时代，对吧？
your family occupied this land
你的家族曾居住在这片土地上。
then this fist might be yours
那么，这只拳头可能就是你的了。
That doesn't necessarily mean you can buy it or get it, you know.
但这并不意味着你就能买到或得到它。
You also want a prime urban location
您还需要一个优越的城市位置。
It also needs to be a mountaintop
它还必须是一座山顶
Can you figure this out?
你能解决这个问题吗？
not your turn
还没轮到你呢
Well, this brings us to another issue
嗯，这就引出了另一个问题。
It's just that everyone in China might be quite accustomed to saying
只是在中国，每个人可能都相当习惯说这句话。
Oh well, I can't buy land anyway, right?
唉，反正我也买不起地，对吧？
I buy a house, what am I buying
我买了一套房子，我到底买了什么？
Isn't it just openly available on the market?
难道它不是在市场上公开销售的吗？
right
正确的
You think everything is between buyers
你认为一切都只关乎买家。
the seller has agreed
卖方已同意
Let's go to a trading center, right?
咱们去交易中心吧？
What else is there that can't be sold?
还有什么东西是不能卖的？
Well, in the vast majority of other countries around the world
嗯，在世界其他绝大多数国家都是如此。
Many things are not so easily movable.
很多东西并不容易搬动。
the family has held it for generations
这个房子是家族世代拥有的。
The family might be in a family trust or something like that.
这个家庭可能加入了家族信托或其他类似的机构。
just like the old Dutton kind
就像老达顿家族那样
Right, yeah
对，是的
Is this something you can just buy whenever you want?
这是你想买就能买的东西吗？
Can you sell it whenever you want?
你想卖就卖，可以随时卖吗？
Well, it really depends on luck, right?
嗯，这真的要看运气，对吧？
depends on financial capability
取决于财务能力
It also depends on a little bit of luck, hmm.
这其中也需要一点运气，嗯。
You're saying this property insurance is a must-have, aren't you?
你是说这份财产保险是必备的，对吧？
Unfortunately
很遗憾
just like the other insurances I mentioned before
就像我之前提到的其他保险一样。
you almost have no choice
你几乎别无选择
You have no choice, understand?
你别无选择，明白吗？
Some people say this real estate company, well, many people are saying this.
有人说这家房地产公司，嗯，很多人都这么说。
getting back to the point
回到正题
Fortunately, I still had some experience in real estate.
幸运的是，我还有一些房地产方面的经验。
Let me interrupt
让我打断一下。
Sorry
对不起
ALEX uh
亚历克斯呃
East's protection of property rights
东方对财产权的保护
I dare not say it's the best in the world
我不敢说它是世界上最好的。
at least it is much stronger compared to the West
至少与西方相比，它要强大得多。
The Eastern Power has no property tax
东部电力公司没有房产税。
personal residences
私人住宅
limited to personal residences
仅限个人住宅
Commercial properties are subject to taxes, while personal residences are not
商业地产需要缴税，而个人住宅则不需要。
You, you, your property fees
你，你，你的房产费
Even if you don't pay the property management fees
即使你不支付物业管理费
at most they'll cut you off
最多也就是断了你的电。
cut off water and electricity
切断水和电
You can still make a scene
你仍然可以制造场面
don't let them cut off your water and electricity
别让他们切断你的水和电。
right
正确的
That homeowners association cannot sell your house
业主协会无权出售你的房子
right
正确的
You don't have to buy insurance
你不必购买保险。
Even if you do this and that, you do a lot of good things, uh...
即使你做了这样那样的事，你也做了很多好事，嗯……
Everyone, open your property certificate
各位，请打开你们的房产证
You might have forgotten about it
你可能已经忘记了这件事。
and then go to that bedside drawer to look for it
然后去床头柜抽屉里找它。
Turn to the second last page of the property ownership certificate
翻到房产所有权证书的倒数第二页。
If I remember correctly
如果我没记错的话
It should be called the right of pledge
它应该被称为质押权。
For the vast majority of easterners, the term 'other rights'
对于绝大多数东方人来说，“其他权利”一词
There has only ever been one thing called a mortgage loan
抵押贷款只有一种东西。
right
正确的
Only when you take out a loan
只有当你贷款时
Your certificate carries someone else's rights
你的证书承载着他人的权利。
This is called an easement, where there's something on the easement, you see.
这叫做地役权，地役权范围内有东西，你看。
In Xida, as mentioned earlier
如前所述，在西达。
HA stands for the homeowners association
HA 代表业主协会。
The homeowners' association checks if your grass has grown to 12 centimeters
业主协会会检查你的草坪是否长到 12 厘米。
as stipulated by the community
根据社区的规定
But the limit is ten centimeters, and it's exceeded by two centimeters
但限度是十厘米，而这里超出了两厘米。
step forward onto the ground for you
向前一步，走到地面上，为你而来。
Take note if you've painted the wrong color.
注意不要涂错颜色。
Note down whether it has been pre-registered
记下是否已预先注册。
before you lift it
在你举起它之前
you cannot transfer it
你不能转让它
may even accumulate over time
甚至可能随着时间的推移而积累
may involve fines
可能涉及罚款。
involves auction
涉及拍卖
Not only is this about the insurance
这不仅仅关乎保险。
You don't have insurance
你没有保险
You still want to pay property taxes for that
你仍然想为此缴纳房产税。
What else do you want
你还想要什么？
Is it possible for him to be registered at the upper level of power?
他有可能被列入权力高层吗？
In the West
在西方
Why do people dislike buying houses
为什么人们不喜欢买房
just because you bought a house
仅仅因为你买了一套房子
you're the sucker
你才是傻瓜
Everyone can take a cut from you
每个人都可以从你身上分一杯羹。
Yes
是的
Ah, and even more commonly, including many historically accumulated issues
啊，更常见的情况是，还包括许多历史遗留问题。
A resident behind me has an easement right
我身后的一位居民拥有地役权
can pass through the road from my property
可以从我的房产穿过这条路
I want to repair my road
我想修路
must leave enough width for him
必须给他留出足够的空间。
enough what
够了什么
or else there will be another lawsuit
否则将面临另一场诉讼。
Otherwise there will be some contact of mine with this piece of land
否则，我将与这块土地产生某种联系。
On one hand, there is a water
一方面，有水
Me a slope cannot exceed a certain limit
坡度不能超过一定限度
Otherwise, if I am upstream
否则，如果我在上游。
I will tilt toward my neighbor's downstream
我会向下游邻居的方向倾斜。
What is the water causing it to accumulate?
是什么水导致它积聚？
It's another water-related product
这是另一种与水有关的产品。
You buy a piece of land
你买了一块地
There are many items in the subsequent property rights content
后续产权内容中包含许多项目。
and even includes hydrographic charts
甚至还包括水文图表
Why
为什么
because I've done it
因为我已经做到了。
You and you, you open your property deed
你，还有你，你打开你的房产证
Damn clean
干净得一尘不染
Sometimes it increases painful consumption
有时它会增加痛苦的消费
It's about many of your essential or quasi-essential items
它关系到你许多必需品或准必需品。
pull off this kind of thing
搞定这种事
He forces you to spend money
他强迫你花钱。
And this money makes you spend it in a particularly painful way
而这笔钱会让你以一种特别痛苦的方式花掉它。
To put it bluntly, even if you spend less, it's still not enough
坦白地说，即使你少花钱，也还是不够。
Spending less only slightly reduces your pain
少花钱只能略微减轻你的痛苦
but still painful
但仍然很痛苦
You can only avoid the pain by spending a lot of money
只有花很多钱才能避免痛苦。
And this relief from pain only lasts for a short while
而且这种疼痛缓解只能持续很短的时间。
Ah
啊
You might say this is creating a false sense of necessity, right?
你可能会说，这制造了一种虚假的必要性，对吧？
Right, creating rigid demand, mhm
没错，人为制造僵化需求，嗯。
Fiercely creating rigid demand
猛烈制造僵化需求
The GDP is skyrocketing
国内生产总值正在飙升
Oh my god
我的天啊
And also, with this home insurance
而且，还有这份房屋保险
What exactly does it cover?
它具体涵盖哪些内容？
My house is hit by an earthquake
我的房子被地震袭击了。
caught fire
着火了
flooded
被淹
He can compensate me.
他可以补偿我。
Hey, does everyone still remember the Los Angeles wildfire?
嘿，大家还记得洛杉矶山火吗？
You bought home insurance, right?
你买了房屋保险，对吧？
I secretly canceled your insurance just a few days before the wildfire came.
就在山火来临前几天，我偷偷取消了你的保险。
You can't not buy Me insurance
你不能不给我买保险
but I can cancel at any time
但我可以随时取消。
Got it
知道了
That's exactly why I say it's a painful consumption.
正因如此，我才说这是一种痛苦的消费。
that you have to buy
你必须购买
but in reality, it's practically useless
但实际上，它几乎毫无用处。
Well, they're just doing business, right?
他们只是在做生意而已，对吧？
They first went to the California court
他们首先去了加利福尼亚州法院。
that legislation over there, right
那边的立法，对吧？
In a certain year's legislation, a clause was added called the 'at, uh, policy'
在某一年的立法中，增加了一项名为“at, uh, policy”的条款。
What is an as well policy
什么是良好政策
that is fair and reasonable for both parties
对双方而言都是公平合理的
It can be terminated if it's reasonable, right?
如果理由合理，就可以终止合同，对吧？
You pay for one day at a time
你按天付费
I provide insurance coverage day by day, right?
我每天都在提供保险保障，对吧？
We are fair, reasonable, and equal parties, alas.
可惜，我们都是公平、理性、平等的各方。
Well then
那好吧
Now it's June
现在是六月
July is just around the corner
七月即将到来
After a series of complex calculations by my insurance company
经过我的保险公司一系列复杂的计算后
Microstar aquitard groundwater layer calculation
Microstar 隔水层地下水层计算
I think the probability of a risk occurring in July
我认为七月份发生风险的概率很高。
may exceed the rate I charge
可能超过我收取的费用。
But then I did the calculations again
但我后来又重新计算了一遍。
I realized that if I increase the premium further
我意识到，如果我进一步提高保费……
may trigger adverse selection
可能引发逆向选择
A lot of people would come to me to cancel their insurance, right?
很多人都会来找我取消他们的保险，对吧？
Then what I'm doing is not increasing this rate
那么我所做的，并不是提高这个比率。
Because I know that increasing it would be thankless and unappreciated
因为我知道增加它既得不到感激，也不会有人领情。
I also couldn't collect that money, right?
我也没能收到那笔钱，对吧？
and it also ruins my reputation
而且这还会损害我的名誉。
Then I'll just give it to you
那我就直接给你吧
I'll just cut it off
我把它剪掉就行了。
Sigh, it's written in the law
唉，法律上是这么规定的。
I can
我可以
You and I are fair and reasonable parties, right?
你我都是公平合理的当事人，对吧？
You pay to get on the bus
你需要付费才能上车。
I'm not charging for this
我不会为此收费。
Of course I can ask you to get off the car.
我当然可以要求你下车。
We are fair and reasonable.
我们公平合理。
Ah, everyone, think about it
啊，各位，好好想想。
So, in plain terms, does this home insurance actually work or not?
那么，简单来说，这种房屋保险到底有没有用呢？
he said it's a high-risk period means it's a high-risk period
他说这是高风险时期，意思就是这是高风险时期。
The definition of the risk period is not in your hands
风险期的定义并非由您决定。
even though you're the one who bought the insurance
即使是你自己购买的保险。
The insurance company says it's now a high-risk period.
保险公司表示，现在是高风险时期。
they can cut off your coverage at any time
他们可以随时终止你的保险。
Got it
知道了
Some say it's a gamble
有人说这是赌博。
This is not a bet
这不是打赌
This is a one-sided breach of agreement
这是单方面违反协议的行为。
Bro, this is no bet at all.
兄弟，这根本不是打赌。
Of course it's a bet
当然，这是一场赌博。
You can also choose not to report at any time
您也可以随时选择不举报。
I can also opt out at any time, right?
我也可以随时选择退出，对吗？
but as the property owner
但作为业主
You are legally required
您依法必须
You must have these items like water insurance and fire insurance.
您必须购买水险和火灾险等保险。
no matter who you choose
无论你选择谁
You have to find PICC
你需要找到 PICC 导管。
right?
正确的？
Of course
当然
Here
这里
There are only three insurance companies in total
总共只有三家保险公司。
Both are controlled by the same shareholder
两者均由同一股东控制。
Don't ask, okay
别问了，好吗？
They'll just say it's the free market at work
他们只会说这是自由市场运作的结果。
There are actually only two options
实际上只有两种选择
Take it or leave it
接受或拒绝
As for why the one from the neighboring county can't come, you say
至于为什么邻县的人来不了，你说……
right
正确的
Shall we present the legal provisions?
我们是否应该列出相关法律条文？
We can request that you consider our county, right
我们可以请求您考虑一下我们县的情况，对吗？
must have this insurance license
必须持有此保险执照
still requires 123
仍然需要 123
He doesn't have it
他没有。
How could he be allowed to sell it?
他怎么能被允许出售它？
Don't forget the ultraviolet light box for jaundice we mentioned earlier.
别忘了我们之前提到的用于治疗黄疸的紫外线灯箱。
Every Smith agent has to make money.
每个史密斯经纪人都得赚钱。
Ah, so all I can say is, sigh, it's still too much
唉，我只能说，唉，还是太多了。
This group of people can really twist this law to their advantage.
这群人真的能利用这条法律为自己谋利。
That's really
那真是
Really, huh, sigh
真的吗，唉……
Just like this?
就是这样吗？
Hahahaha hey
哈哈哈哈，嘿
Really
真的
Sometimes that kind of rhetoric from above can easily lead to trouble
有时候，这种来自上层的言论很容易引发麻烦。
Sigh, rest assured cultural relics
唉，放心吧，文化遗迹
I can say this without fear
我可以毫无畏惧地说出这句话。
peanuts haven't been eaten even after recording an entire episode
即使录制完一整集节目，花生也没吃。
Ah, I really am Chinese
啊，我真是个中国人。
I'm not afraid to eat this either
我也不怕吃这个。
This is the goodness of being Chinese that you've seen
这就是你所看到的中国人的优点。
You slam your Chinese passport on the table
你把中国护照重重地摔在桌子上。
He really takes you seriously
他真的很认真对待你。
Hmm, you're saying how come it's only Route Level 1?
嗯，你是说为什么只有 1 级路线？
Don't you understand Victoria's selective breeding of races?
你难道不了解维多利亚州对不同种族进行的选择性育种吗？
Ah, and why was he promoted to Route Level 1?
啊，他为什么会被提升到 1 级路线？
Because he's not Anglo-Saxon.
因为他不是盎格鲁-撒克逊人。
The name Luigi is an Italian name.
路易吉（Luigi）是一个意大利名字。
Right, the Anglo-Saxons just aren't cut out for it
没错，盎格鲁-撒克逊人根本不适合做这件事。
This brings us to the inherent flaws of the Anglo-Saxon people.
这就引出了盎格鲁-撒克逊民族固有的缺陷。
Luigi is of Italian descent
路易吉是意大利裔
He is indeed not an Anglo-Saxon.
他确实不是盎格鲁-撒克逊人。
He had black hair and black eyes
他有一头黑发和一双黑眼睛
He is of Italian nationality.
他是意大利国籍。
Pure Anglo-Saxons are still not quite up to par
纯种盎格鲁-撒克逊人仍然不够格
Sigh, the Anglo-Saxons are just too tolerant.
唉，盎格鲁-撒克逊人真是太宽容了。
How about letting you Anglo-Saxons witness the old-school Roman way, huh?
不如让你们盎格鲁-撒克逊人见识一下古老的罗马方式，怎么样？
Hahaha, yeah, when you think about it, it's still damn hard to take
哈哈，是啊，仔细想想，还是很难接受。
Some say Americans don't know how to resist
有人说美国人不懂得如何抵抗
except with Luigi
除了路易吉
Actually, Luigi isn't of Anglo-Saxon descent.
事实上，路易吉并非盎格鲁-撒克逊人后裔。
Luigi really isn't, ah
路易吉真的不是，啊
Sigh, sometimes dark hair and dark eyes
唉，有时是黑发和黑眼睛
Is this in some sense an imitation of the Romans?
这在某种意义上是对罗马人的模仿吗？
Right, hmm
对，嗯。
Is it the Anglo-Saxons or are they just too tolerant
是盎格鲁-撒克逊人的性格使然，还是他们过于宽容了？
Queen Victoria's selection is still so persuasive
维多利亚女王的选择至今仍然如此具有说服力。
Brothers, hmm
兄弟们，嗯。
Listen to me, kids, okay
孩子们，听我说，好吗？
This is Victoria's strict selection
这是维多利亚的严格筛选标准。
Brothers, there's nothing to criticize.
兄弟们，没什么可批评的。
Alright bro, let me check what time it is
好的兄弟，我看看现在几点了。
It's past nine o'clock.
现在已经过了九点。
Alright guys, I'm calling it a night. Goodbye, everyone.
好了各位，今天就到这里吧。再见，各位。
I'm out too
我也退出了。
Rest rest rest rest rest, um
休息休息休息休息休息，嗯
Wait a second, let me take a screenshot of this
等一下，让我截个图。
Take a screenshot
截屏
Um, OK, I'm done for the day.
嗯，好了，我今天就到这里了。
Good night, bros
晚安，兄弟们。
Good night, good night, good night, bro
晚安，晚安，晚安，兄弟。
Thank you Brother Sanna 4H for the 30 popularity tickets
感谢 Sanna 4H 兄弟赠送的 30 张人气券。
Thank you to the brother JERRY for sending the popularity tickets
感谢杰瑞兄弟寄来的人气门票。
Thank you, brothers
谢谢各位兄弟。
Thank you thank you, good night good night bros
谢谢谢谢，晚安晚安兄弟们
Thank you thank you thank you
谢谢，谢谢，谢谢！